<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Slides on Gavin Rozzi</title>
    <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/slides/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Slides on Gavin Rozzi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2013-2019 Gavin Rozzi</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.gavinrozzi.com/slides/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Reimagining the police scanner in the era of the SDR</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/slides/ocradio-cyberspectrum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/slides/ocradio-cyberspectrum/</guid>
      <description>📶 Reimagining the police scanner in the era of the SDR Taking scanning to the next level using distributed RTLSDR receivers &amp;amp; open source software
Presented by Gavin Rozzi Cyberspectrum #23 @ DEF CON 2018
August 9th, 2018
SDR has the potential to expand public knowledge while reducing cost &amp;amp; complexity The problem with hardware scanners Hardware scanners are expensive Digital scanners especially those capable of newer digital protocols are pricey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Researching the opiod crisis using OPRA</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/slides/opiatecrisis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/slides/opiatecrisis/</guid>
      <description>Researching the opiod crisis with OPRA Using public records 📄 for a data-driven approach to combatting addiction 💊
Presented by Gavin Rozzi Ocean County College
February 15th, 2019
Who Am I? - B.A. Political Science, Stockton University 
- Former teaching assistant, constitutional law 
- Background in web development, tech &amp;amp; journalism 
Background on OPRA The Open Public Records Act
- A state law, N.J.S.A. 47:1A-1 et seq.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using OPRAmachine to file public records requests without the hassle</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/slides/montclair/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/slides/montclair/</guid>
      <description>📑: Using OPRAmachine to file public records requests without the hassle Streamline your public records requests with New Jersey&amp;rsquo;s public records request &amp;amp; research platform.
Gavin Rozzi Presented by the Montclair University Center for Cooperative Media
August 21st, 2018
Transparency matters but getting results from NJ government can be be difficult OPRAmachine is a tool that is simplifying public records requests in New Jersey OPRAmachine allows users to send &amp;amp; track public records requests It then publishes all documents &amp;amp; correspondence online OPRAmachine is built on the premise that everything should be public.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>