<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gavin Rozzi on Gavin Rozzi</title>
    <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gavin Rozzi on Gavin Rozzi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2013-2018 Gavin Rozzi</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Document Production in Rozzi v. OAG</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/rozzi-oag/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/rozzi-oag/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently obtained &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gavinrozzi.com/files/OAGemaillogs.pdf&#34;&gt;the following documents&lt;/a&gt; from the New Jersey Attorney General&amp;rsquo;s Office (OAG) which were produced in response to a court order isued in my lawsuit against the OAG. The documents were copies of email logs that show messages sent and received by the OAG&amp;rsquo;s custodian of records, who is responsible for complying with the provision of the New Jersey Open Public Records Act (OPRA) by way of responding to requests made under the state freedom of information law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gavinrozzi.com/files/Rozzi-AG Verified Complaint.pdf&#34;&gt;My lawsuit&lt;/a&gt;, which was filed in Mercer County Superior Court, resulted in an an order for the Attorney General&amp;rsquo;s office to produce the (redacted) copies of the documents that I originally requested back in November, 2017. Additional delays were added by the fact that the documents required a significant number of redactions due to the OPRA custodian&amp;rsquo;s additional responsibilities in the OAG, such as those related to homeland security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My attorney, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pashmanstein.com/attorney/cj-griffin&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CJ Griffin, Esq.&lt;/a&gt; ultimately prevailed over the creative legal argument advanced by the AG&amp;rsquo;s Office. The AG&amp;rsquo;s legal position was particularly novel because the legal briefings cited OPRA cases as old as 2004 while essentially attempting to pretend the New Jersey Supreme Court&amp;rsquo;s ruling in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nj.com/politics/index.ssf/2017/03/nj_supreme_court_ruling_could_reshape_what_governm.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Paff v. Galloway Township&lt;/a&gt; (2017).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;I have an &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/OPRA?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#OPRA&lt;/a&gt; hearing tomorrow. Last year our Supreme Court ruled in Paff v Galloway that a request for a log of emails is a valid OPRA request. The State refuses to follow it and is asking the court to apply case law from 2004, as if Paff never happened. Updates to come&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; CJ Griffin, Esq. (@CJGriffinEsq) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/CJGriffinEsq/status/983515006556934144?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;April 10, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both the documents that were recently produced by the OAG in response to Judge Mary Jacobson, A.J.S.C.&amp;rsquo;s ruling in this case are available on the original &lt;a href=&#34;https://opramachine.com/request/email_logs_for_bruce_solomon_oag#incoming-3248&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;request thread on OPRAmachine.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Conversation With Jeff Epstein and Patrick Duff Re: OPRA &amp; Open Government</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/jeffpatrickopra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/jeffpatrickopra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently spoke with Citizens&amp;rsquo; Media TV&amp;rsquo;s Jeff Epstein and Patrick Duff for an audio interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/peopleconversations/omgavinpatrick&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Our conversation&lt;/a&gt; centered on the Open Public Records Act (OPRA), transparency &amp;amp; open government issues centered on my work with public records and how the three of us have made use of my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/opramachine/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;OPRAmachine&lt;/a&gt; platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Epstein is an independent journalist who I&amp;rsquo;ve previously collaborated with on various projects, and he also has a role with OPRAmachine where has serves as one of the site&amp;rsquo;s administrators since its inception in 2017. He covers local and naitonal political issues and streams local government meetings on &lt;a href=&#34;https://citizensmedia.tv/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Citizens&amp;rsquo; Media TV.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Duff is one of the most active users of OPRAmachine, having used the site to file numerous public records agencies to state agencies as well as local governments primarily in Camden County. He explained how he is using OPRAmachine further his research into the historical significance of properties tied to Martin Luther King in southern New Jersey. He explained how he used the site to streamline and track all of the public records requests he files to support his historical research. One of the public records requests Duff filed through OPRAmachine resulted in a lawsuit against the City of Camden, which he largely prevailed in since the recording of this interview. All of Duff&amp;rsquo;s public records requests and documents provided by government agencies in response &lt;a href=&#34;https://opramachine.com/user/patrick_duff&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;can be viewed on the site here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Listen to the full interview:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;no&#34; allow=&#34;autoplay&#34; src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/440247858&amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;show_teaser=true&amp;visual=true&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discussing OPRAmachine&#39;s Impact With WLFR Radio&#39;s Bill Watt</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/watt-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/watt-interview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On on April 5th, 2018 I joined WLFR Radio&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Watt&amp;rsquo;s The Move&lt;/strong&gt;, Stocton University&amp;rsquo;show
own radio show that focuses on poliitics and public affairs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my one hour segment I discussed my work on several fronts. Our interview began with
talk of my work with my first and most successful project, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/politicsoc/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ocean County Politics&lt;/a&gt;
and later pivoted to my work with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/opramachine/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;OPRAmachine&lt;/a&gt; freedom of information portal and
how it is making New Jersey government more transparent as a result of its impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final segment of the show was spent discussing my analysis of the upcoming 2018 primary races, specifically with regard to the senate
and congressional seats that will be in play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WLFR is the student-run radio station of Stockton University, and broadcasts
in Galloway Township, NJ on 91.7 MHz and also has &lt;a href=&#34;http://wlfr.fm/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;a feed online&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See below for a video of me discussing OPRAmachine:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/plugins/video.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Fgavinrozzi%2Fvideos%2F10208691053793200%2F&amp;show_text=0&amp;width=267&#34; width=&#34;267&#34; height=&#34;476&#34; style=&#34;border:none;overflow:hidden&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowTransparency=&#34;true&#34; allowFullScreen=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Libertarians for Transparent Government v. New Jersey State Police</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/njsplawsuit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/njsplawsuit/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;new-jersey-state-police-held-accountable-in-court-for-stalling-on-public-records-requests&#34;&gt;New Jersey State Police held accountable in court for stalling on public records requests&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The case Libertarians for Transparent Government v. New Jersey State Police was an important case that revealed
unacceptable practices by the New Jersey State Police.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The case revealed a pattern and practice of failure to comply with the requirements of the state&amp;rsquo;s Open Public Records Act (OPRA) after a judge in the case issued a ruling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I participated in the case by way of filing a certification detailing my experience with attempting to obtain helicopter usage logs
for then-New Jersey Governor Chris Christie&amp;rsquo;s usage of State Police helicopters. My certification details my own experience with the State Police and how they took repeated extensions prior to providing me with heavily redacted helicopter usage records.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;more-details-about-the-case&#34;&gt;More details about the case&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gavinrozzi.com/files/Cert of Gavin Rozzi for Libertarians-SP2.pdf&#34;&gt;Read my certification&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B66zM58TlOVKRTZERjNvNm1xM0U/view&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Read the full complaint&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OPRAmachine</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/opramachine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/opramachine/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;opening-up-new-jersey-government&#34;&gt;Opening up New Jersey government&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://opramachine.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;OPRAmachine.com&lt;/a&gt; is a first of its kind government transparency project that I recently launched to serve the citizens of the state of New Jersey. The site is powered by the New Jersey &lt;strong&gt;Open Public Records Act&lt;/strong&gt; (OPRA), a freedom of information law that allows any citizen of the state to request public records from state and local government agencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-it-works&#34;&gt;How it works&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OPRAmachine is breaking down barriers by explaining aspects of the OPRA request process. The site allows any citizen to easily file a legally valid public records request and includes a directory that currently includes all 565 municipalities in the state, as well as various state and county governmental agencies. The site has enabled requesters to obtain thousands of pages worth of public records, helping to shine a light on some of the more obscure elements of New Jersey state and local government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A unique benefit that OPRAmachine provides is that once a public entity provides documents in response to a request, the documents are subsequently stored in the site&amp;rsquo;s database and made public, allowing the entire public to be able to reap the benefits. This model reduces duplicate requests and serves to further the OPRA law&amp;rsquo;s purpose of maximizing the citizenry&amp;rsquo;s knowledge of public affairs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;thousands-of-pages-released&#34;&gt;Thousands of pages released&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since its inception in October, 2017, the OPRAmachine platform has enabled the release of thousands of pages of government documents. Our database of public bodoies currently includes all 565 municipalities in New Jersey, with more public bodies being added on a regular basis.
The site has been making an impact and has been used as a research tool by public officials, journalists and activists seeking to obtain authoritative information about public entities in the state. We recently added a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.opramachine.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; that includes detailed information about the process of making a request through the site, as well as reference material concerning the legal and site administration issues that may arise as a result of the site&amp;rsquo;s operation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;praise-for-opramachine&#34;&gt;Praise for OPRAmachine&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;One of the most important tools making New Jersey government more transparent.&amp;rdquo;
- &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/CitizensMediaTV/posts/1661839777229733&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Citizens Media TV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Thanks to Gavin Rozzi’s “OPRA Machine” website, the Atlantic County Government can no longer pretend to be transparent. Now they must do it for real.&amp;rdquo;
- &lt;a href=&#34;https://atlanticcountynews.com/2017/11/29/atlantic-county-sexual-harassment-payouts-fly-right-below-the-radar/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Atlantic County News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The latest installation of our Alaveteli software, OPRAmachine, is an interesting new use of the platform. Rather than covering a whole country, as most of the other Alaveteli installations around the world do, it services just a single US state.&amp;rdquo;
- Gemma Moulder, of the UK-based mySociety, which &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mysociety.org/2017/12/06/introducing-opramachine-tackling-political-corruption-in-new-jersey/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;created the open-source software&lt;/a&gt; that powers the OPRAmachine platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;opramachine-s-impact-in-new-jersey&#34;&gt;OPRAmachine&amp;rsquo;s impact in New Jersey&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following four months of work, I reflected on some of the accomplishments of the web service &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.opramachine.com/four-months-later-opramachine-making-an-impact/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;in this blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;by-the-numbers&#34;&gt;By the numbers&lt;/h3&gt;

Since October, 2017, OPRAmachine has seen:
&lt;ul&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1751&lt;/strong&gt; public records requests&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1370&lt;/strong&gt; followup messages sent&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;201&lt;/strong&gt; registered users&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;782&lt;/strong&gt; public bodies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;80&lt;/strong&gt; annotations added to requests&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;151&lt;/strong&gt; tracked requests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h3 id=&#34;latest-opra-requests&#34;&gt;Latest OPRA requests&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Powered by the OPRAmachine API&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  
  
   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://opramachine.com/request/employee_payroll_request_as_of_m&#34; target=&#34;&#34;&gt;Employee Payroll request as of March 31, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Requested from: &lt;a href=&#34;https://opramachine.com/body/ochd&#34; target=&#34;&#34;&gt;Ocean County Health Department&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Requested by: Dan&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Status: &lt;strong&gt;Successful.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Please see attached OPRA Response letter &amp;amp;amp; the documents requested.

 If you would like the documents in another format or there are any issues
 with t...&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  
   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://opramachine.com/request/elected_official_salaries_benefi_24&#34; target=&#34;&#34;&gt;Elected Official Salaries, Benefits, and Reimbursements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Requested from: &lt;a href=&#34;https://opramachine.com/body/spotswood_borough&#34; target=&#34;&#34;&gt;Spotswood Borough&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Requested by: Charlie Kratovil&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Status: &lt;strong&gt;Response&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Dear Mr. Kratovil,  as far as question #5 &amp;amp;amp; #6, the elected officials do
 not and did not receive any reimbursement pay during any year they have
 been...&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  
   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://opramachine.com/request/opra_requests_283&#34; target=&#34;&#34;&gt;OPRA Requests&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Requested from: &lt;a href=&#34;https://opramachine.com/body/pemberton_township&#34; target=&#34;&#34;&gt;Pemberton Township&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Requested by: ASK NJ Media Co.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Status: &lt;strong&gt;Response&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Payroll reports are attached to this e-mail.

 




Sunshine Dashiell&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h3 id=&#34;chart-of-requests&#34;&gt;Chart of requests&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opramachine.com/foi-live-creation.png&#34; alt=&#34;OPRAmachine graph&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Main &lt;a href=&#34;https://opramachine.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;OPRAmachine&lt;/a&gt; website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read updates about the project at our &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.opramachine.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ocean County Radio Live</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/ocradiolive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/ocradiolive/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-new-way-to-scan-ocean-county&#34;&gt;The new way to scan Ocean County&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ocradio.live/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ocean County Radio Live&lt;/a&gt; is taking the technical complexity and hassle out of radio scanning in Ocean County, New Jersey. This website was launched in late January, 2018 and since that date has continued to stream &amp;amp; archive multiple police, fire &amp;amp; EMS radio channels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This website is powered by the latest software defined radio (SDR) technology to process the streams of digital data produced by the Ocean County trunked radio system and also record analog conventional systems used by some departments &amp;amp; squads. The SDRs record radio transmissions and upload them to the site&amp;rsquo;s server, which allows them to easily be played and archived online. When Ocean County activates the new 700 MHz P25 Phase II radio system, our receivers will only need a simple software configuration change in order to pick up the new system&amp;rsquo;s signal. This flexibility makes SDR radios superior for this particular application, allowing us to provide a wide amount of channels on our system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The system has a major advantage over all traditional forms of radio scanning as it uses &amp;ldquo;time shifting&amp;rdquo; like a DVR does when recording multiple overlapping TV shows, ensuring that &lt;strong&gt;no transmissions are missed&lt;/strong&gt;, since traditional scanners can only hold on just one channel - potentially missing other calls that could be taking place on different talkgroups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This system is powered by multiple R820T SDRs running on a desktop computer and connected to the front-end web server accessed by end users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As our base of users continues to grow, I intend on covering more radio systems and adding them to this system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;coming-soon-to-oc-radio-live&#34;&gt;Coming soon to OC Radio Live&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Little Egg Harbor Police P25&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ocean County Probation P25&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OC-ALERT Fire &amp;amp; EMS paging channel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;atlantic-county-version-coming-soon&#34;&gt;Atlantic County version coming soon&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are also hoping to setup a similar system for the new Atlantic County P25 Phase II system that recently became fully operational. Check back here for more details on that at a later date. Some of these projects will likely be under the domain name &lt;strong&gt;p25.stream.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://ocradio.live/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ocean County Radio Live&lt;/a&gt; web application is based on the open-source &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ScanOC/trunk-player&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Trunk-Player&lt;/a&gt; Django project. So far, I have contributed one &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ScanOC/trunk-player/commit/8dbc011c96bf19951bc9fa1fbf6c37d5e215dc4a&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;pull request&lt;/a&gt; to the upstream open source software that powers the project, and I plan to contribute more in the future as my schedule allows.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forked River Amateur Radio Club</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/frnjarc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/frnjarc/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;serving-the-forked-river-nj-amateur-radio-community&#34;&gt;Serving the Forked River, NJ amateur radio community&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Forked River Amateur Radio Club is a new amateur radio club formed to serve amateur radio community of Forked River, NJ and surrounding areas. I currently serve as both the vice president and webmaster of the club. We anticipate on pursuing several projects through this club, such as 2 meter FM repeater and 70 cm band DMR system to cover the Lacey area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the impact that weather events like Hurricane Sandy have had on the region, we felt that an amateur radio group focused exclusively on our area would be beneficial to both the local amateur radio community as well as the public at large.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://frnjarc.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;View the club&amp;rsquo;s website here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JerseyLeaks</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/jerseyleaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/jerseyleaks/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;enabling-whistleblowers-to-report-public-corruption&#34;&gt;Enabling whistleblowers to report public corruption&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jerseyleaks.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;JerseyLeaks&lt;/a&gt; is a public corruption whistleblowing &amp;amp; transparaency initiative. The site serves as a collaborative journalism tool that allows
sources to confidentially leak documents to reporters using an encrypted online system. The documents are encrypted at rest and in transit using the OpenPGP public keys of journalists using the open-source &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.globaleaks.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Globaleaks&lt;/a&gt; software, ensuring the privacy of sources.
The system allows whistleblowers with knowledge of public corruption to submit documents to journalists who may publish them as a part of an investigative story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project has been a collaborative effort and other journalists are invited to join the platform, with further details being on the JerseyLeaks website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;more-about-jerseyleaks&#34;&gt;More about JerseyLeaks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jerseyleaks.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;View the main JerseyLeaks website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://submit.jerseyleaks.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Submit documents to JerseyLeaks securely&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ocean County Politics</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/politicsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/politicsoc/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ocean-county-s-source-political-news-commentary&#34;&gt;Ocean County&amp;rsquo;s source political news &amp;amp; commentary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ocean County Politics is an independent news website that covers politics and public affairs in the greater Ocean County, NJ region. Ocean County Politics has become known for publishing in-depth accounts of county and municipal governmental activities and behind-the-scenes activities that influence the county&amp;rsquo;s political climate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to providing insightful commentary and news, the site also features reader contributed op-eds and letters to the editor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;follow-ocean-county-politics&#34;&gt;Follow Ocean County Politics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://politicsoc.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Read Ocean County Politics here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rozzi v. Lacey Township Board of Education</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/rozzivlaceyboe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/rozzivlaceyboe/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fee-demand-for-public-records-declared-unreasonable-and-unwarranted&#34;&gt;Fee demand for public records declared &amp;ldquo;unreasonable and unwarranted&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After being on their docket for close to two years, the New Jersey Government Records Council (GRC) ruled in my favor after I filed a complaint captioned Gavin C. Rozzi v. Lacey Township Board of Education, GRC complaint 2015-224. The GRC ordered the Lacey Township Board of Education to refund an $85 &amp;ldquo;special service fee&amp;rdquo; the board&amp;rsquo;s business administrator imposed for copies of checks that showed the board&amp;rsquo;s contracted attorney received health benefits through a school district plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;question-presented&#34;&gt;Question Presented&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did the Lacey Township Board of Education&amp;rsquo;s imposition of an $85 &amp;ldquo;special service fee&amp;rdquo; for copies of checks that showed the school board attorney - a contracted professional - was receiving health benefits through a district plan violate the Open Public Records Act, N.J.S.A. 47:1A-1 et seq.?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;holding&#34;&gt;Holding&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The GRC held that the special service fee was &amp;ldquo;unreasonable and unwarranted&amp;rdquo; and issued an interim order compelling the district to refund the fee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I filed the complaint because it was my belief that the true purpose of the fee was the chill public records requests rather than legitimately recover expenses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gavinrozzi.com/files/2015-224.pdf&#34;&gt;Read the full decision from the GRC here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rozzi v. Ocean County Prosecutor&#39;s Office</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/rozzivocp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/rozzivocp/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;New Jersey Government Records Council&lt;/strong&gt; (GRC) ruled in my favor and declared that the
response provided to an Open Public Records Act (OPRA) request was legally insufficient under the OPRA law&amp;rsquo;s requirements. The GRC complaint was filed in 2015 and was adjudicated by the GRC after a nearly two-year wait time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This case was filed at the same time a lawsuit that was filed against the OCPO by open government activist Harry Scheeler. Scheeler&amp;rsquo;s lawsuit sought similar documents as those that were issue in this case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;read-the-grc-s-full-opinion-here&#34;&gt;Read the GRC&amp;rsquo;s full opinion here&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gavinrozzi.com/files/2015-250.pdf&#34;&gt;Read the full decision from the GRC here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Municipal Tax Abatements Policy Briefing</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/publication/tax-abatements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/publication/tax-abatements/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Featured on Rachel Maddow Show</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/rachelmaddow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/rachelmaddow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During the 2016 presidential election, I worked to fiercely cover the state, local &amp;amp; federal elections occurring within the communities of Ocean County, New Jersey for my website &lt;a href=&#34;https://politicsoc.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ocean County Politics&lt;/a&gt;. During this time, my reporting on the cancellation of a GOP fundraiser held for then-Vice Presidential candidate Mike Pence was featured on an episode of the Rachel Maddow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;fb-root&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script&gt;(function(d, s, id) {
  var js, fjs = d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0];
  if (d.getElementById(id)) return;
  js = d.createElement(s); js.id = id;
  js.src = &#39;https://connect.facebook.net/en_US/sdk.js#xfbml=1&amp;version=v2.11&amp;appId=111682819550624&#39;;
  fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js, fjs);
}(document, &#39;script&#39;, &#39;facebook-jssdk&#39;));&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;fb-video&#34; data-href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/therachelmaddowshow/videos/10153990933079067/&#34; data-width=&#34;500&#34; data-show-text=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;blockquote cite=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/therachelmaddowshow/videos/10153990933079067/&#34; class=&#34;fb-xfbml-parse-ignore&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/therachelmaddowshow/videos/10153990933079067/&#34;&gt;Pence fundraiser interest too low to be worth his time&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two Mike Pence fundraisers cancelled for lack of interest, one in Nebraska, one in New Jersey.

Is lack of interest in Pence events a sign of the air leaving the Trump balloon?&lt;/p&gt;Posted by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/therachelmaddowshow/&#34;&gt;The Rachel Maddow Show&lt;/a&gt; on Tuesday, October 11, 2016&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ocean County Scanner News</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/ocscannernews/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/ocscannernews/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;live-ocean-county-police-fire-ems-calls-as-they-happen&#34;&gt;Live Ocean County police, fire &amp;amp; EMS calls as they happen&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ocscanner.news/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ocean County Scanner News &lt;/a&gt; is a network of radio and emergency services enthusiasts who listen to police scanners and post live news updates via their &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/OceanCountyScannerNews/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Facebook page.&lt;/a&gt; I designed the groups&amp;rsquo;s website in addition to setting up a live scanner feed server running the Icecast live streaming server. The main live feed covers the Ocean County Trunked Radio system and several other local conventional channels for police, fire &amp;amp; EMS agencies serving Ocean County. We are planning more additions to the live feed as time and resources allow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of the breaking news updates posted on Ocean County Scanner News are reflective of breaking news stories that later are reported in the media - oftentimes days later as many outlets wait for official press releases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My involvement with the page is primarily with serving as the live feed administrator, but I will occassionally post scanner calls as time allows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;scanner-programming-services&#34;&gt;Scanner programming services&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am available to provide scanner programming services if you have a scanner that you are looking to use to monitor local channels. This is something that can be discussed on a case-by-case basis to determine if I have the proper cable / software in order to work with your scanner. Please &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gavinrozzi.com/#contact&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;contact me&lt;/a&gt; to discuss your needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;listen-live&#34;&gt;Listen live&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ocscanner.news/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;View the Ocean County Scanner News website here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ocradio.live/scan/default&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Use the OC Radio Live online police scanner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ocscanner.news:8000/stream&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Listen to the main live scanner feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ocscanner.news:8000/south&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Listen to the southern live feed (Lacey, Barnegat &amp;amp; Waretown)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview with CIO Magazine</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/ciomag/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/ciomag/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CIO Magazine &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cio.com/article/2460827/search/seo-sem-top-25-diy-tips-for-better-seo.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;wanted my take&lt;/a&gt; on tips you can take to improve search engine rankings for small business websites for an article entitled &amp;ldquo;Top 25 DIY Tips for Better SEO.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what I had to say:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WordPress is, in essence, a blogging platform. But many businesses use it as the content management system for a complete website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yoast’s WordPress SEO Plugin (free) is a favorite among many SEO experts. “I recommend it to my clients because it allows the automation and easy integration of important SEO strategies,” says Gavin Rozzi, president, Gavin Rozzi Technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drupal and Joomla are two worthy WordPress alternatives, Rozzi says. “These free, open-source content management systems come with an assortment of plug-ins that automate much of the SEO workload.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
