<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gavin Rozzi on Gavin Rozzi</title>
    <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gavin Rozzi on Gavin Rozzi</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2013-2019 Gavin Rozzi</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Response to NJ Law Journal Article</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/njlawjournal-response/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/njlawjournal-response/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-am-writing-in-response-to-jonathan-frodella-s-article-that-appeared-in-the-january-17th-2019-edition-of-the-new-jersey-law-journal-entitled-victims-of-serious-crimes-need-more-protection-under-opra-https-finance-yahoo-com-news-victims-serious-crimes-more-protection-120055094-html&#34;&gt;I am writing in response to Jonathan Frodella’s article that appeared in the January 17th, 2019 edition of the New Jersey Law Journal entitled &lt;a href=&#34;https://finance.yahoo.com/news/victims-serious-crimes-more-protection-120055094.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;“Victims of Serious Crimes Need More Protection Under OPRA.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Frodella - whose article was written from the perspective of an attorney that advises municipal clerks - contends that services that automatically publish public records requests and responses such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://opramachine.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;OPRAmachine&lt;/a&gt;, which I founded in 2017, serve to create a “complication” for custodians of records by not requiring individuals to certify whether or not they were convicted of an indictable offense due to the remote possibility of a convicted criminal requesting information about their victims.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Online services that automatically publish government records to the world have complicated this issue further by potentially reframing the analysis of victims’ privacy interests,&amp;rdquo; Frodella says.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first launched the OPRAmachine service, our default request template included language that allowed individuals to certify whether or not they were convicted of an indictable offense. However, after discussing the necessity of including this certification with our legal team, we decided to remove it at their recommendation to protect the privacy interests of our requestors and in recognition of the fact that this is not a concern for the overwhelming majority of the thousands of public records requests that have been processed by our service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed, OPRA does not limit the right of convicted felons to file OPRA requests. Even currently incarcerated inmates have a right to file OPRA requests. Therefore, there is no reason why a person would need to disclose their conviction status in order to obtain the overwhelming majority of government records. As such, including it on our forms would be extraneous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the OPRA statute is written now, &lt;a href=&#34;https://law.justia.com/codes/new-jersey/2013/title-47/section-47-1a-2.2/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;N.J.S.A. 47:1A-2.2&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; permit a government agency to ask the requestor about their conviction status given the context of their request. However, this should take place only in the rare circumstances where they need to ascertain whether the person was seeking records “pertaining to the person’s victim or the victim’s family.” Otherwise, there is no reason why a requestor would need to reveal whether or not they have a conviction history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Against that background, we chose to follow the advice of our legal team and drop the criminal conviction certifications from the default request template on OPRAmachine last year. So, while there may be potential concerns about the small chance of OPRA custodians releasing records to perpetrators of serious crimes, this is a concern that only applies to an infinitesimally small amount of requests. Records custodians should not throw the baby out with the bathwater and assume the worst about services that automatically publish public records online because of this remote possibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is settled case law that the documents and records released by custodians of records are themselves government records subject to disclosure under our state freedom of information law. See &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://caselaw.findlaw.com/nj-superior-court-appellate-division/1768547.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Scheeler v. Office of the Governor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, 448 N.J. Super. 333 (App. Div. 2017), so in line with the public policy of transparency codified in OPRA, there is absolutely no reason why public records requests and responses should not be published online for the benefit of the public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a perfect world, the innovative model adopted by OPRAmachine would be the default for all government agencies so that the public can be kept apprised of the activities of the bodies they support with their hard-earned tax dollars. That is what my work has centered on for the past two years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created OPRAmachine in response to the dismal state of affairs for compliance with the Open Public Records Act in New Jersey. My own past experiences dealing with state &amp;amp; local government gone awry in my capacity as an independent journalist and transparency advocate have informed my opinions about the law’s implementation and state of compliance in New Jersey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a representative sample of some of the OPRA cases I was involved in where government agencies were found to have broken the law, see &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gavinrozzi.com/legal/rozzivlaceyboe&#34;&gt;Rozzi v. Lacey Township Board of Education&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, GRC complaint 2015-224, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gavinrozzi.com/legal/rozzivocp&#34;&gt;Rozzi v. Ocean Cty. Prosecutor’s Office&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, GRC complaint 2015-250 and &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gavinrozzi.com/legal/njsplawsuit/&#34;&gt;Libertarians for Transparent Government v. New Jersey State Police.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t just take my word for it: A 2015 study released by the Center for Public Integrity &lt;a href=&#34;https://publicintegrity.org/accountability/new-jersey-gets-d-grade-in-2015-state-integrity-investigation/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;gave New Jersey a “D” grade in transparency and accountability and an &amp;ldquo;F&amp;rdquo; for public access to information&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is unacceptable. Our state can and must do better, and right now OPRAmachine is one of the only platforms that is pushing back against the current lack of transparency and accountability in New Jersey government by publishing public records and tracking compliance with the law. Government agencies at all levels serve an important purpose by enforcing the law. It&amp;rsquo;s only fair that they comply with their statutory obligations to disclose public records under OPRA and respond to legally valid requests such as those facilitated by my service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result of the activity on the site, we are producing &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gavinrozzi/opra-data&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the only statewide dataset that is tracking compliance with the law&lt;/a&gt; by type of government agency, including state offices, counties and independent authorities. Officials must be more proactive in fulfilling their transparency obligations to the public that they serve, and OPRAmachine is an important tool for remedying the current climate for transparency in the Garden State.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thesis of Frodella’s commentary would make one think that there is an urgent problem affecting victims of crime. Contrary to his assertions, the sky is not falling for victim privacy. The truth of the matter is that the concerns raised by Mr. Frodella only apply to an exceptionally small number of requests. Records custodians are properly charged with the responsibility of determining whether a request is being submitted by an individual with a conviction seeking information pertaining to their victim(s). Additional exemptions are not necessary, nor should they be added in future iterations of OPRA reform bills pending in the legislature, as they risk diluting the effectiveness of OPRA as an accountability tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I am grateful for Mr. Frodella&amp;rsquo;s suggestion that agencies subject to OPRA be more &amp;ldquo;user friendly,&amp;rdquo; his advocacy of agencies emphasizing the use of official paper forms is problematic for those concerned with transparency. That remedy is at best anachronistic, and at worst, a way for  local governments to be even less transparent by keeping public records requests hidden from the public at large, turning back the clock on recent advances if they were to be adopted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Frodella says that government agencies should emphasize the use of official forms, he correctly stops short of advising governments that the use of an official form should be required. Forcing requestors to fill out a paper form is archaic, reactionary and a waste of paper as electronic records have become ubiquitous. Some records custodians attempt to ignore the court&amp;rsquo;s decision in &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.courtlistener.com/opinion/2107856/renna-v-county-of-union/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Renna v. Cty. of Union, 407 N.J. Super. 230&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; (App. Div. 2009) and inaccurately claim that they will not process an OPRA request without an official form being completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Appellate Division in &lt;em&gt;Renna&lt;/em&gt; made it crystal clear that OPRA requests cannot be denied solely on the basis that they are not submitted on an agency&amp;rsquo;s official form. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://opramachine.com/search/opra%20form/all&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;OPRAmachine database has numerous examples of this&lt;/a&gt;, and fortunately, in many instances requestors pushed back against these additional bureaucratic hurdles erected by clerks to hinder access to public information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Government agencies must embrace the public policy considerations that have been enshrined in OPRA by taking steps to be proactively transparent. We must change the culture of government agencies from viewing OPRA as an unfunded mandate from Trenton. OPRA is an important check and balance and a vehicle for ensuring government accountability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frodella also mentioned how the pending case &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gavinrozzi.com/files/Coombs%20et%20al%20-%20Monmouth.pdf&#34;&gt;Coombs et al. v. Cty. of Monmouth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; may impact OPRAmachine and other similar platforms. I joined as a plaintiff in the Coombs matter to stand up for the users of my platform who have been negatively impacted by the unprofessional behavior and bad faith exhibited by Monmouth County officials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Coombs&lt;/em&gt; matter made it to Monmouth County Superior Court&amp;rsquo;s docket when one of the county’s employees negligently failed to redact private information concerning County Prosecutor Christopher Grammicioni. Immediately upon being notified of the breach, we removed the documents upon being contacted by an assistant county counsel. &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.opramachine.com/site-policies-and-procedures/content-removal/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Our stated terms of service&lt;/a&gt; request that government agencies put their reasons in writing for requesting the removal of documents, but we waived it due to exigency of the situation. There’s no denying that the entire situation could have been avoided had the county properly reviewed the documents before releasing them to the public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By Monmouth County’s own admission in subsequent court filings, this incident was not the first time that county employees failed to properly redact OPRA documents. The only difference is that because OPRAmachine existed, the public was able to know that the breach had occurred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How many other times have government agencies unwittingly compromised private information without the public having the benefit of knowing? That is the real question that should be asked here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Monmouth County government and its legal counsel instead chose to attempt to craft a new exemption by administrative fiat in response to the negligence and lack of care exercised by their employees, likely to save themselves future embarrassment and exercise additional control over the OPRA process as is typical in the capricious fiefdoms that have sprung up in New Jersey state &amp;amp; local government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As our attorney Walter Luers wrote in a brief for the case &amp;ldquo;Attempts by public agencies to force records custodians to use specific forms or to make followup requests after they have been denied access to records or to limit the right to make a request to citizens of this State have failed. This case is no different.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://opramachine.com/request/monmouth_county_division_of_soci_4#incoming-3976&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Their new legally specious OPRA policy&lt;/a&gt; says that the county will deny any OPRA request solely on the basis that the email address indicates the records will be automatically published on the internet. In addition to demonstrating an ignorance of how modern technology works, the policy adopted by Monmouth County contravenes both the letter and spirit of the Open Public Records Act.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, as the court observed in &lt;a href=&#34;https://caselaw.findlaw.com/nj-superior-court/1492514.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Asbury Park Press v. Ocean Cty. Prosecutor&amp;rsquo;s Office&lt;/a&gt;, 374 N.J. Super. 312 (Law. Div. 2004):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearly, the court must always maintain a sharp focus on the purpose of OPRA and resist attempts to limit its scope, absent a clear showing that one of its exemptions or exceptions incorporated in the statute by reference is applicable to the requested disclosure. The salutary goal, simply put, is to maximize public knowledge about public affairs in order to ensure an informed citizenry and to minimize the evils inherent in a secluded process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This, the county cannot do, so both myself and another administrator of the site joined as plaintiffs in OPRAmachine user Jennifer Coombs&amp;rsquo; lawsuit to ensure that the Monmouth County government cannot be permitted to shirk their responsibility to comply with the law just because they don&amp;rsquo;t like the fact that public records requests are being shared with the very public they exist to serve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no recognized legal precedent that supports the gravamen of the legal theory advanced by Monmouth County to justify their policy, which is an unprecedented blow to transparency in county government and as such, this policy perpetuates a manifest injustice to users of OPRAmachine and those similarly situated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, transparency and accountability are both vital to ensuring the health of a thriving democracy, both locally and nationally. Government agencies must fulfill their disclosure obligations so that voters may be fully informed when voting in elections and be knowledgeable of the activities of local officials who govern on their behalf. When they fail to do so, they do a disservice not only to their citizens, but to the values that our nation was founded on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://marketing.rozzi.media/email/preview/7&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;As I pledged in my press release announcing our case against Monmouth County last fall,&lt;/a&gt; our team is prepared to mount a campaign of litigation against any agency that challenges the validity of requests submitted through the OPRAmachine service.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview with PrincetonInfo</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/princetoninfo-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/princetoninfo-interview/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;princeton-i-was-interviewed-by-u-s-1-news-publishers-of-the-website-princetoninfo-http-princetoninfo-com-this-week&#34;&gt;PRINCETON - I was interviewed by U.S. 1 News, publishers of the website &lt;a href=&#34;http://princetoninfo.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PrincetonInfo&lt;/a&gt; this week.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interview appeared both online and in the website&amp;rsquo;s print newspapers, which are distributed in the Mercer County region.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.gavinrozzi.com/img/coverUS1.png&#34; alt=&#34;The cover of the print newspaper where the interview was published&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From their article:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone who has ever tried to request government records in New Jersey knows that authorities and bureaucracies make the information request process intentionally difficult and inconvenient, to discourage the public from seeking information that is required by law to be public. The OPRAMachine bypasses some of this hassle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This new tool is clearly a godsend for journalists, and has already been used to good effect. For example, Charlie Kratovil of New Brunswick Today used the OPRAMachine to request payroll records from every town in New Jersey and audited each one to find where towns were violating labor laws.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Rozzi says the OPRAMachine is also useful for other groups. Average citizens, law firms, and businesspeople have been using the site to file thousands of requests since it launched last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rozzi says people in the real estate, property management, and construction have been using it to research properties they are interested in. “They usually look for open permits or liens on a particular property,” he says. “They will say there’s nothing on this property, or maybe there is something, and they’ll take that information and use it in whatever they end up doing for their clients. They prepare a report making sure it’s clear of liens, almost similar to a title search,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;click-here-to-read-the-full-story-https-princetoninfo-com-opramachine-makes-requesting-records-easy-for-everyone&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://princetoninfo.com/opramachine-makes-requesting-records-easy-for-everyone/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Click here to read the full story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A data-driven approach to combatting addiction</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/talk/occopiatecrisis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/talk/occopiatecrisis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After the presentation, Ocean County College addiction studies students are going to implement the concepts discussed in the talk &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gavinrozzi.com/files/ALDC 101 Term Project Assignment.pdf&#34;&gt;in order to complete their term project.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project is going to see students use public records to identify trends in overdose incidents and drug activity in their communities. The students will use the data to write a memo to their local decisionmakers and make three recommendations about how to combat addiction, making citations to the data they obtain.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rozzi Wins Excellence in Local News Award</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/innovatelocal-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/innovatelocal-award/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.gavinrozzi.com/img/gavin_award2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Gavin Rozzi, holding the Excellence in Local News Award&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PRESS RELEASE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GREEN BROOK, NJ&lt;/strong&gt; – Gavin Rozzi, editor of Ocean County Politics, announced that he and his team received an award for their work with government transparency and the Open Public Records Act (OPRA).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rozzi.media&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Rozzi Media Group&lt;/a&gt;, publishers of Ocean County Politics, was awarded the Excellence in Local News Award in the “Innovate Local” category at a ceremony held on Friday in Middlesex County. The award is issued to journalists who “…used new and emerging technologies or strategies to enhance and improve the value and impact of their reporting efforts.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The award was given for our work with OPRAmachine, a statewide website that helps people submit public records requests to government agencies throughout New Jersey. The site’s innovative approach to government transparency features the automatic publication of public records requests and responses made to government agencies throughout New Jersey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the website has launched, it has processed over 4000 public records requests made to 963 government agencies within the state. Its freely searchable archive features 16 gigabytes of documents obtained from requests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Gavin and his team added all 565 municipalities and 21 counties to their OPRAmachine database and then pursued educational and advocacy partnerships to improve and increase the service’s impact across the state,” said Joe Amditis, Associate Director of the Center for Cooperative Media at Montclair University.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.gavinrozzi.com/img/awardpresentation.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Gavin Rozzi, holding the Excellence in Local News Award&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The website, which has thousands of active users, includes features for auditing government agencies for their compliance with OPRA’s 7-day deadline for responses to requests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ocean County Politics Editor Gavin Rozzi
“Rozzi and his team also hosted a free webinar for NJ News Commons partners where they trained journalists and other stakeholders on how to maximize the efficiency of their public records requests using OPRAmachine,” Amditis added. The webinar can be viewed for free online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2018, a Pro tier was launched to support the rapid growth of the OPRAmachine service. Our partners in the construction / property management, legal &amp;amp; private investigative industries have quickly adopted the system to streamline their requests. We have also received positive feedback from multiple municipal clerks in Monmouth &amp;amp; Ocean Counties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We are truly honored to receive this recognition for our government transparency platform,” Rozzi said in a statement. “The health of our democracy and society requires that public agencies fulfill their obligation to be transparent. Decisions that impact taxpayers need to be done in a public process, and I am thankful that our service has made a positive impact in empowering citizens by restoring transparency &amp;amp; accountability to New Jersey government.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rozzi would like to acknowledge Jeff Epstein, the editor of Citizens Media TV who has served as a volunteer administrator for the site, in addition to OPRAmachine assistant and OCP Staff Writer Carlie Gibson, who spearheaded efforts to update the site’s database with additional school districts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also would like to thank Charlie Kratovil, a former New Brunswick mayoral candidate and the editor of New Brunswick Today. Kratovil has been an early supporter of both Ocean County Politics and OPRAmachine, and we will be bringing him on as an administrator of OPRAmachine later this month. He has been using the batch request functionality of the site to audit minimum wage compliance at New Jersey municipalities.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OPRAmachine: 1 Year Later</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/om-1-year-later/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/om-1-year-later/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;one-year-ago-today-i-launched-opramachine-https-opramachine-com-and-it-has-been-making-a-significant-impact-on-all-levels-of-new-jersey-government-since-its-inception&#34;&gt;One year ago today, I launched &lt;a href=&#34;https://opramachine.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;OPRAmachine&lt;/a&gt;, and it has been making a significant impact on all levels of New Jersey government since its inception.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OPRAmachine began with a simple premise: to maximize government transparency in New Jersey by automatically publishing public records requests &amp;amp; responses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The site&amp;rsquo;s unique approach to public records helps individuals get answers to their personal OPRA requests, but also serves the entire community by contributing to a growing statewide archive of public knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Public records that normally would have been provided to just one requestor are now stored in perpetuity and infinitely accessible to others that may have an interest in them using the service, something that proprietary solutions like GovQA fail to adequately do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New Jersey is a state that has been known for its many layers of government, with 565 municipalities and countless school districts, MUAs and other independent authorities. OPRAmachine makes navigating the various layers of government simple for both those new to requesting public records and those with experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than hunting for email addresses on town websites or dealing with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www16.state.nj.us/NJ_OPRA/department.jsp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;poorly designed online systems that are relics of a bygone era in web design&lt;/a&gt;, OPRAmachine is realizing the dream of a single, unified &amp;amp; open platform for transparency in all 21 counties of the state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first came up with the idea of creating a site like OPRAmachine in late 2016 and began working on testing and customizing the &lt;a href=&#34;https://alaveteli.org/deployments/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;open-source code&lt;/a&gt; that powers the site throughout 2017. By October of last year, we pulled back the curtain and let the public start making requests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The early days of the site were wrought with technical challenges, and high demand in the first weeks resulted in OPRAmachine&amp;rsquo;s server being brought down multiple times. After overcoming those initial challenges, we were proud to have no major downtime during business hours that would have prevented responses to public records requests being received by our server.&lt;/p&gt;

Since October, 2017, OPRAmachine has seen:
&lt;ul&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4403&lt;/strong&gt; public records requests&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3159&lt;/strong&gt; followup messages sent&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;646&lt;/strong&gt; registered users&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1119&lt;/strong&gt; public bodies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;135&lt;/strong&gt; annotations added to requests&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;376&lt;/strong&gt; tracked requests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;In the days and months that followed the launch, the site has since taken on a life of its own, and I continue to be impressed by the new use cases that have emerged as more people began to adopt the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have an incredible, diverse group of users who have benefitted from the site. Our users represent a cross-section of the stakeholders that benefits from increased access to public information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They include attorneys, traditional &amp;amp; digital journalists, college professors, real estate &amp;amp; property management professionals, public officials, private investigators, environmental consultants and perhaps most importantly, private citizens interested in learning more about the inner workings of their state &amp;amp; local government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of our users have benefitted from OPRAmachine without even making a request of their own. Some receive email alerts for specific towns and keywords found in requests, while our full collection of documents is indexed by search engines like Google and often appears in their results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever their individual use case may be, the common thread among them has been that our paperless, streamlined process has simplified the public records request process while saving time &amp;amp; resources for all concerned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OPRAmachine could not have seen the level of success that it has without the support it has received from our stakeholders &amp;amp; community. I&amp;rsquo;d like to thank all of our users, especially our most persistent requestors as well as our volunteer administrator, Jeff Epstein, who has handled many issues with the site &amp;amp; inquiries from users when I am unavailable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would also like to thank the government officials that have had a dialogue with me in the course of running the service &amp;amp; dealing with administrative issues. I found it heartening that many of the township clerks I engaged with appreciated the mission of the site and the increased transparency it provides residents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also deserving of recognition is our legal counsel, CJ Griffin, Esq. and Walter Luers, Esq. They have both been tremendous assets and we would be at a significant disadvantage without their expertise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I am optimistic about the success we have attained in just one short year, there are some significant hurdles that we still must overcome to ensure the continued success of OPRAmachine. Going forward, the challenge will be to educate certain &lt;a href=&#34;https://aeanj.org/wp-content/uploads/AEA-Authority-View-Summer-2018.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;reactionary government officials&lt;/a&gt; about the benefits of the service and advocating for legislative reform that favors electronic disclosure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is my goal to work with government agencies as much as we can, but when all else fails, we will pursue litigation against those government agencies that &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/monmouth-opra-case/&#34;&gt;arbitrarily &amp;amp; unlawfully refuse to process requests&lt;/a&gt; on the basis that they are submitted through the site, and encourage our users to do the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In closing, we&amp;rsquo;ve covered a lot of ground during the first year of OPRAmachine&amp;rsquo;s existence, but our work is far from over. Thank you all of those who have supported us on this journey.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Jersey Shore Online Re: Monmouth County OPRAmachine Lawsuit</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/monmouth-opra-case/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/monmouth-opra-case/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-recently-spoke-with-jersey-shore-online-https-www-jerseyshoreonline-com-ocean-county-lawsuit-questions-when-county-can-share-public-records-about-my-participation-in-a-multi-plaintiff-open-public-records-act-lawsuit-against-the-monmouth-county-nj-government-over-their-refusal-to-answer-requests-through-my-site-opramachine-https-opramachine-com&#34;&gt;I recently spoke with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jerseyshoreonline.com/ocean-county/lawsuit-questions-when-county-can-share-public-records/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jersey Shore Online&lt;/a&gt; about my participation in a multi-plaintiff Open Public Records Act lawsuit against the Monmouth County, NJ government over their refusal to answer requests through my site &lt;a href=&#34;https://opramachine.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;OPRAmachine&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lawsuit stems from the county&amp;rsquo;s refusal to answer legally valid public records requests submitted through the site, which automatically publishes public records requests &amp;amp; responses in all 21 counties of New Jersey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In its first year of existence, the civic technology and open government website - the first of its kind targeting New Jersey state &amp;amp; local government - has streamlined and modernized the public records request process in a paperless and easy to use process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monmouth County answered requests through the site without issue throughout 2017 and most of 2018 &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.opramachine.com/monmouth-opra-lawsuit/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;until one of their employees failed to redact confidential information.&lt;/a&gt;. When the county employees made a mistake, I took swift corrective action to remove the confidential material within 1 day of being contacted about the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the county chose to punish users of my site and refuse to answer any requests through the site after the incident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is unaccaptable and an obstruction of the county&amp;rsquo;s transparency obligations under OPRA, the state&amp;rsquo;s freedom of information law. I joined in the case to stand up for our users, who have faced stalls and delays on their records requests. OPRAmachine users includ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the portion of the story where I was quoted:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since announcing the lawsuit at the end of September, Rozzi has been working on changes to OPRAmachine. In an Oct. 9 email to Jersey Shore Online, he explained he’s been working to address privacy concerns raised by Monmouth County.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“By the end of the month, we anticipate that our changes will allow OPRAmachine to detect and automatically redact social security numbers to protect privacy interests, something that no other proprietary public records solution (that we are aware of in NJ) does,” Rozzi wrote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a separate email the same day, Rozzi explained exactly why he filed suit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We want the court to order Monmouth County to do as they have previously done and honor the legally valid public records requests submitted to them by our users. We hope that the lawsuit will stop the county from treating public records requests differently because they originate from the OPRAmachine service. To remedy the county’s obstruction of the public records request process, we are urging the court to strike down the county’s unprecedented and overreaching policy that limits access to public information and find them in violation of the law.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;read-the-full-story-at-jersey-shore-online-https-www-jerseyshoreonline-com-ocean-county-lawsuit-questions-when-county-can-share-public-records&#34;&gt;Read the full story at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jerseyshoreonline.com/ocean-county/lawsuit-questions-when-county-can-share-public-records/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jersey Shore Online&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;You have to read Rozzi&#39;</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/insider-100/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/insider-100/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-was-honored-to-be-included-on-the-latest-edition-of-insider-nj-s-media-100-list-https-www-insidernj-com-wp-content-uploads-2018-10-insider-20100-20media-20publication-202018-pdf&#34;&gt;I was honored to be included on the latest edition of Insider NJ&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.insidernj.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/Insider%20100%20Media%20Publication%202018.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Media 100 List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.gavinrozzi.com/img/insider100.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Insider 100&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OPRAmachine Webinar at Montclair</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/montclair-webinar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/montclair-webinar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/_1E2tWOOWzU&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday, August 21st, 2018 I made my way up to the Montclair University Center for Cooperative Media to present about my work creating the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gavinrozzi.com/projects/opramachine/&#34;&gt;OPRAmachine&lt;/a&gt; New Jersey statewide freedom of information portal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The webinar was attended by both journalists and other individuals interested in making use of the advanced public records research capabilities provided by our platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you to the folks at the Center who helped put all of this together, and thank you to our attendees who asked insightful questions!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video: Defeating redactions on poorly redacted documents</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/redactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/redactions/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/0NnuA8RMyiY&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re like me and frequently deal with requesting public records, then you&amp;rsquo;ll be accustomed to receiving documents that have blocks of text redacted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Redactions are most often used by government officials to apply exemptions to the various federal and state public records law. Often, they&amp;rsquo;ll be used to obscure information that may breach confidentiality protections or needlessly harm the personal privacy of individuals. In other instances, redactions are somtimes abused to keep the lid on politically damaging revelations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not all redactions are created equal. In most cases, public entities are able to suitably redact documents either using computer-based solutions or with a good old fashioned black marker and copy machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes public entities get it wrong and end up using programs such as Microsoft Office or other basic editors that weren&amp;rsquo;t designed with permanently removing redacted information in mind, which allows the digitial files to be edited to reveal the information that was intended to be kept hidden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Flordia, a newspaper recently took a document that was publicly posted on an official websited and used computer software to remove the redactions and report on the confidential information contained in the publicly available report regarding Parkland school shooter Nikolas Cruz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Florida judge who presided over public records litigation concerning the original release of the report quickly blasted the newspaper, and demonstrated technical ignorance with regard to how the details were obtained by the newspaper&amp;rsquo;s reporters. School board lawyers attempted to frame the publication of the information as a violation of a previous court order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Video of the judge&amp;rsquo;s remarks was quickly posted to social media, where it circulated:
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Tough to watch. &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/7sSD40Wa5o&#34;&gt;https://t.co/7sSD40Wa5o&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Gavin Rozzi (@gavroz) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/gavroz/status/1030224010532057089?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;August 16, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my own video embedded above in this blog post, I use one of my own past public records requests to demonstrate how removing redactions and accessing hidden material is possible when public officials improperly attempt to redact information. The video shows the end result of me using Adobe Acrobat to delete the black boxes of text used to &amp;ldquo;redact&amp;rdquo; information from email logs provided in response to a 2017 public records request from a New Jersey school district.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While these instances are not common, journalists owe it to themselves to double check the documents that they receive in response to their public records requests, as sometimes the mistakes of government agencies may work to the benefit of your story.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview with AEA-NJ Newsletter</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/aea-nj-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/aea-nj-interview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My work with OPRAmachine recently saw me interviewed by the newsletter of an organization that represents the interests of local and county utilities authorities around the state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eric San Juan, a writer for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aeanj.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Association of Environmental Authorities of New Jersey&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s newsletter, interviewed me earlier in the summer about the impact of my statewide freedom of information platform, OPRAmachine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The AEA-NJ was interested in OPRAmachine because their member authorities are subject to the state&amp;rsquo;s freedom of information law, the New Jersey Open Public Records Act. Many of those authorities have been receiving requests through OPRAmachine and the interview provided an opportunity to communicate my platform&amp;rsquo;s benefits to citizens, public officials and other stakeholders with an interest in obtaining public records from New Jersey state and local government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The article and interview were written from the perspective of member authorities and how OPRAmachine may impact them. It also included commentary from a public official who expressed their personal opinions about the site and compliance with New Jersey&amp;rsquo;s OPRA law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://aeanj.org/wp-content/uploads/AEA-Authority-View-Summer-2018.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The full article&lt;/a&gt; appears in the AEA-NJ&amp;rsquo;s summer, 2018 edition of their &amp;ldquo;Authority View&amp;rdquo; newsletter, which is accessible to member municipal and county utilities authorities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Article preview:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.gavinrozzi.com/img/aeanjarticle.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Article screenshot&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reimagining the police scanner in the era of the software defined radio</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/talk/ocradiodefcon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/talk/ocradiodefcon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recorded video of talk:

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/Yhuis48SQGk&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be speaking about my experience implementing open source software and working the RTLSDR platform to create an online timeshifting police, fire &amp;amp; EMS scanner that outperforms commercially availalble hardware scanners in many respects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use the video link above to watch this talk live on the date of the event. The time of this event has been changed to Eastern Standard Time for its posting on this website due to the difference in timezones.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using OPRAmachine to file public records requests without the hassle</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/talk/montclair/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/talk/montclair/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recorded video of webinar:

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/_1E2tWOOWzU&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join me in late August at the Montclair University &lt;a href=&#34;https://centerforcooperativemedia.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Center for Cooperative Media&lt;/a&gt; to talk about my recent work with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/opramachine&#34;&gt;OPRAmachine&lt;/a&gt; and give a step-by-step demonstration along with taking audience questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here is their official announcement of the event, copied below:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Opening up New Jersey government, one request at a time.&amp;rdquo; That&amp;rsquo;s the tagline of OPRAmachine.com, a free tool created by New Jersey&amp;rsquo;s own Gavin Rozzi and available for all to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every citizen has the right to access public records held by state &amp;amp; local government agencies under the New Jersey Open Public Records Act (OPRA). By law, they have to respond. The problem is, the process for requesting those documents isn&amp;rsquo;t always as easy and straightforward as it should be – until now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join this webinar and Rozzi will show you the simple, step-by-step process for filing OPRA requests and browsing OPRAmachine to see what public records and information others have requested&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Register for the event at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/using-opramachine-to-file-public-records-requests-without-the-hassle-tickets-48653465826?aff=efbeventtix&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Eventbrite&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big upgrades to OC Radio Live</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/ocrl-update-72918/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/ocrl-update-72918/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Today I am proud to announce that we have added a significant number of new channels to &lt;a href=&#34;https://ocradio.live&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ocean County Radio Live&lt;/a&gt;, my online police fire &amp;amp; EMS scanner and archive service.
The service now supports listening to two 700 MHz digital trunked radio systems, Ocean County&amp;rsquo;s and the New Jersey Interoperability Communications System, which hosts channels for the State Police,
Fish &amp;amp; Wildlife and numerous other state and local agencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding these new systems to our service is important because many people are missing out on listening to these systems because of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2LJX7TX&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;high price&lt;/a&gt; of purchasing a new scanner,
along with the technical complexity of programming the scanner. My service eliminates both of these problems, while adding several exciting new features that make scanning even better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In partnership with &lt;a href=&#34;https://ocscanner.news/2018/07/29/ocsn-scanner-less-dispatchers-wanted/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ocean County Scanner News&lt;/a&gt; we have made significant infrastructure and server upgrades to support the addition of more channels through the purchase of additional software defined radios.
We hope to have additional channels added soon, along with restoring our coverage of the barrier island, Toms River and Brick, which had to be temporarily taken offline to make room for the 700 MHz upgrades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, it goes without saying that there is a cost to provide this service. We would like to thank all those who have purchased a premium subscription, as it directly support additional upgrades.
Please consider purhasing a &lt;a href=&#34;https://ocradio.live/plans/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;premium archive access plan&lt;/a&gt; to listen our archives and support the development of OC Radio Live, or consider &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patreon.com/gavinrozzi&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;supporting me on Patreon&lt;/a&gt; to enable future public service web development &amp;amp; transparency projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;new-jersey-interoperability-communications-sytstem-njics-p25-phase-ii&#34;&gt;New Jersey Interoperability Communications Sytstem (NJICS) - P25 Phase II&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ocradio.live/scan/nj-interoperability-com-sys/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Click to begin scanning this system&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://ocradio.live/scan/default/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;scan all channels&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sample channels:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ocradio.live/tg/howell-police/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Howell Township Police Dispatch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ocradio.live/scan/new-jersey-transit-police/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;New Jersey Transit Police&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ocradio.live/scan/garden-state-parkway/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Garden State Parkway Patrols&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ocradio.live/scan/new-jersey-fish-wildlife/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;New Jersey Fish &amp;amp; Wildlife&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ocradio.live/scan/monoc-paramedics/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MONOC Paramedics and Medevac&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ocradio.live/scan/new-jersey-turnpike/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;New Jersey Turnpike Patrols&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ocean-county-trunked-radio-system-p25-phase-ii&#34;&gt;Ocean County Trunked Radio System - P25 Phase II&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ocradio.live/scan/ocean-county-p25/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Click here to begin scanning the system&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://ocradio.live/scan/default/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;scan all channels&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sample channels:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ocradio.live/tg/fire-ems-dispatch/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Fire &amp;amp; EMS Dispatch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ocradio.live/tg/ocua-central/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ocean County Utilities Authority&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ocradio.live/tg/oc-security-p25/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ocean County Security&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MORE&lt;/strong&gt; coming soon!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OPRAmachine update: The $1000 email metadata &amp; other pushback from government agencies</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/621-om-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/621-om-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was once again interviewed by &lt;a href=&#34;https://citizensmedia.tv/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Citizens&amp;rsquo; Media TV&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; Jeff Epstein about my work with public records &amp;amp; transparency via the OPRAmachine statwewide freedom of information portal that I run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Epstein serves as one of the site&amp;rsquo;s volunteer administrators and in this podcast recorded on June 21st, 2018 we discuss some of the challenges that we have encountered running the site, including pushback from government agencies, fee demands for public records &amp;amp; more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Listen to the full interview:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;no&#34; allow=&#34;autoplay&#34; src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/462904968&amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;show_teaser=true&amp;visual=true&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rozzi v. Office of the Attorney General</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/legal/rozzivoag/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/legal/rozzivoag/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;attorney-general-s-office-violated-public-records-law-by-witholding-email-logs&#34;&gt;Attorney General&amp;rsquo;s Office violated public records law by witholding email logs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Legal Counsel: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pashmanstein.com/attorney/cj-griffin&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CJ Griffin, Esq.&lt;/a&gt; - Pashman Stein Walder Hayden&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The New Jersey Attorney General&amp;rsquo;s Office was found to have violated the Open Public Records Act by denying my request for copies of email logs for the OAG&amp;rsquo;s custodian of records. I requested the email logs as a part of my advocacy on behalf of my statewide freedom of information website, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/opramachine/&#34;&gt;OPRAmachine&lt;/a&gt;. The email logs provided insight into the practices of OAG when it comes to handling OPRA requests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;question-presented&#34;&gt;Question Presented&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Was the New Jersey Attorney General&amp;rsquo;s Office&amp;rsquo;s denial of a request for copies for email logs - on the basis that all of the logs should be withheld because a portion contained confidential information - a violation of the Open Public Records Act, N.J.S.A. 47:1A-1 et seq.?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;holding&#34;&gt;Holding&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Judge Mary Jacobson, A.J.S.C. held that the Attorney General&amp;rsquo;s refusal to produce the logs as originally requested constituted a violation of OPRA and ordered the OAG to disclose the requested email logs that were responsive to the initial public records request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;outcome&#34;&gt;Outcome&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Attorney General&amp;rsquo;s office eventually complied with the court order and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/rozzi-oag/&#34;&gt;turned over the responsive email logs.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the interest of saving resources, I voluntarily waived the portions of the email logs that did not pertain to the deputy attorney general&amp;rsquo;s other roles outside of complying with the state&amp;rsquo;s Open Public Records Act in order to prevent any further delays to accessing the requested public records.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;case-documents&#34;&gt;Case documents&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gavinrozzi.com/files/Rozzi-AG Verified Complaint.pdf&#34;&gt;Read my verified complaint&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/rozzi-oag/&#34;&gt;Read my blog post about the documents they released&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
