<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Gavin Rozzi</title>
    <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Gavin Rozzi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2013-2018 Gavin Rozzi</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>OPRAmachine Webinar at Montclair</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/montclair-webinar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/montclair-webinar/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;
On Tuesday, August 21st, 2018 I made my way up to the Montclair University Center for Cooperative Media to present about my work creating the OPRAmachine New Jersey statewide freedom of information portal.
The webinar was attended by both journalists and other individuals interested in making use of the advanced public records research capabilities provided by our platform.
Thank you to the folks at the Center who helped put all of this together, and thank you to our attendees who asked insightful questions!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video: Defeating redactions on poorly redacted documents</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/redactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/redactions/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;
If you&amp;rsquo;re like me and frequently deal with requesting public records, then you&amp;rsquo;ll be accustomed to receiving documents that have blocks of text redacted.
Redactions are most often used by government officials to apply exemptions to the various federal and state public records law. Often, they&amp;rsquo;ll be used to obscure information that may breach confidentiality protections or needlessly harm the personal privacy of individuals. In other instances, redactions are somtimes abused to keep the lid on politically damaging revelations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview with AEA-NJ Newsletter</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/aea-nj-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/aea-nj-interview/</guid>
      <description>My work with OPRAmachine recently saw me interviewed by the newsletter of an organization that represents the interests of local and county utilities authorities around the state.
Eric San Juan, a writer for the Association of Environmental Authorities of New Jersey&amp;rsquo;s newsletter, interviewed me earlier in the summer about the impact of my statewide freedom of information platform, OPRAmachine.
The AEA-NJ was interested in OPRAmachine because their member authorities are subject to the state&amp;rsquo;s freedom of information law, the New Jersey Open Public Records Act.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big upgrades to OC Radio Live</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/ocrl-update-72918/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/ocrl-update-72918/</guid>
      <description>Today I am proud to announce that we have added a significant number of new channels to Ocean County Radio Live, my online police fire &amp;amp; EMS scanner and archive service. The service now supports listening to two 700 MHz digital trunked radio systems, Ocean County&amp;rsquo;s and the New Jersey Interoperability Communications System, which hosts channels for the State Police, Fish &amp;amp; Wildlife and numerous other state and local agencies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OPRAmachine update: The $1000 email metadata &amp; other pushback from government agencies</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/621-om-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/621-om-update/</guid>
      <description>I was once again interviewed by Citizens&amp;rsquo; Media TV&amp;rsquo;s Jeff Epstein about my work with public records &amp;amp; transparency via the OPRAmachine statwewide freedom of information portal that I run.
Epstein serves as one of the site&amp;rsquo;s volunteer administrators and in this podcast recorded on June 21st, 2018 we discuss some of the challenges that we have encountered running the site, including pushback from government agencies, fee demands for public records &amp;amp; more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Document Production in Rozzi v. OAG</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/rozzi-oag/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/rozzi-oag/</guid>
      <description>I recently obtained the following documents from the New Jersey Attorney General&amp;rsquo;s Office (OAG) which were produced in response to a court order isued in my lawsuit against the OAG. The documents were copies of email logs that show messages sent and received by the OAG&amp;rsquo;s custodian of records, who is responsible for complying with the provision of the New Jersey Open Public Records Act (OPRA) by way of responding to requests made under the state freedom of information law.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Conversation With Jeff Epstein and Patrick Duff Re: OPRA &amp; Open Government</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/jeffpatrickopra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/jeffpatrickopra/</guid>
      <description>I recently spoke with Citizens&amp;rsquo; Media TV&amp;rsquo;s Jeff Epstein and Patrick Duff for an audio interview.
Our conversation centered on the Open Public Records Act (OPRA), transparency &amp;amp; open government issues centered on my work with public records and how the three of us have made use of my OPRAmachine platform.
Epstein is an independent journalist who I&amp;rsquo;ve previously collaborated with on various projects, and he also has a role with OPRAmachine where has serves as one of the site&amp;rsquo;s administrators since its inception in 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discussing OPRAmachine&#39;s Impact With WLFR Radio&#39;s Bill Watt</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/watt-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/watt-interview/</guid>
      <description>On on April 5th, 2018 I joined WLFR Radio&amp;rsquo;s Watt&amp;rsquo;s The Move, Stocton University&amp;rsquo;show own radio show that focuses on poliitics and public affairs.
During my one hour segment I discussed my work on several fronts. Our interview began with talk of my work with my first and most successful project, Ocean County Politics and later pivoted to my work with the OPRAmachine freedom of information portal and how it is making New Jersey government more transparent as a result of its impact.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Featured on Rachel Maddow Show</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/rachelmaddow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/rachelmaddow/</guid>
      <description>During the 2016 presidential election, I worked to fiercely cover the state, local &amp;amp; federal elections occurring within the communities of Ocean County, New Jersey for my website Ocean County Politics. During this time, my reporting on the cancellation of a GOP fundraiser held for then-Vice Presidential candidate Mike Pence was featured on an episode of the Rachel Maddow.
 (function(d, s, id) { var js, fjs = d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0]; if (d.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview with CIO Magazine</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/ciomag/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/ciomag/</guid>
      <description>CIO Magazine wanted my take on tips you can take to improve search engine rankings for small business websites for an article entitled &amp;ldquo;Top 25 DIY Tips for Better SEO.&amp;rdquo;
Here’s what I had to say:
 WordPress is, in essence, a blogging platform. But many businesses use it as the content management system for a complete website.
Yoast’s WordPress SEO Plugin (free) is a favorite among many SEO experts. “I recommend it to my clients because it allows the automation and easy integration of important SEO strategies,” says Gavin Rozzi, president, Gavin Rozzi Technology.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>