<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Legal on Gavin Rozzi</title>
    <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/tags/legal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Legal on Gavin Rozzi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2013-2018 Gavin Rozzi</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.gavinrozzi.com/tags/legal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Rozzi v. Office of the Attorney General</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/rozzivoag/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/rozzivoag/</guid>
      <description>Attorney General&amp;rsquo;s Office violated public records law by witholding email logs The New Jersey Attorney General&amp;rsquo;s Office was found to have violated the Open Public Records Act by denying my request for copies of email logs for the OAG&amp;rsquo;s custodian of records. I requested the email logs as a part of my advocacy on behalf of my statewide freedom of information website, OPRAmachine. The email logs provided insight into the practices of OAG when it comes to handling OPRA requests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Libertarians for Transparent Government v. New Jersey State Police</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/njsplawsuit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/njsplawsuit/</guid>
      <description>New Jersey State Police held accountable in court for stalling on public records requests The case Libertarians for Transparent Government v. New Jersey State Police was an important case that revealed unacceptable practices by the New Jersey State Police.
The case revealed a pattern and practice of failure to comply with the requirements of the state&amp;rsquo;s Open Public Records Act (OPRA) after a judge in the case issued a ruling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rozzi v. Lacey Township Board of Education</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/rozzivlaceyboe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/rozzivlaceyboe/</guid>
      <description>Fee demand for public records declared &amp;ldquo;unreasonable and unwarranted&amp;rdquo; After being on their docket for close to two years, the New Jersey Government Records Council (GRC) ruled in my favor after I filed a complaint captioned Gavin C. Rozzi v. Lacey Township Board of Education, GRC complaint 2015-224. The GRC ordered the Lacey Township Board of Education to refund an $85 &amp;ldquo;special service fee&amp;rdquo; the board&amp;rsquo;s business administrator imposed for copies of checks that showed the board&amp;rsquo;s contracted attorney received health benefits through a school district plan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rozzi v. Ocean County Prosecutor&#39;s Office</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/rozzivocp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/rozzivocp/</guid>
      <description>The New Jersey Government Records Council (GRC) ruled in my favor and declared that the response provided to an Open Public Records Act (OPRA) request was legally insufficient under the OPRA law&amp;rsquo;s requirements. The GRC complaint was filed in 2015 and was adjudicated by the GRC after a nearly two-year wait time.
This case was filed at the same time a lawsuit that was filed against the OCPO by open government activist Harry Scheeler.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>