<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>legal | Gavin Rozzi</title>
    <link>/tags/legal/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tags/legal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>legal</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/thumbnail.jpg</url>
      <title>legal</title>
      <link>/tags/legal/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coombs et al. v. County of Monmouth</title>
      <link>/legal/coombsmonmouth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/legal/coombsmonmouth/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Legal Counsel: Walter Luers, Esq.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Docket No.: MON-L-003195-18&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Statutory provision at issue: &lt;a href=&#34;https://law.justia.com/codes/new-jersey/2017/title-47/section-47-1a-6/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;N.J.S.A. 47:1A-6(g.) &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Question Presented&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can the Monmouth County, NJ government deny OPRA requests solely on the basis that they will be automatically published online?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Holding&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Monmouth County Superior Court&lt;/strong&gt;, Assignment Judge Lisa P. Thornton ruled that the county violated the Open Public Records Act by denying requests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Outcome&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monmouth County was ordered to respond to records requests via OPRAmachine, ending the denials that took place from 2018-19 under the new policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;case-documents&#34;&gt;Case documents&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/files/Coombsruling.pdf&#34;&gt;Final decision - Coombs et al. v. County of Monmouth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Jersey Shore Online Re: Monmouth County OPRAmachine Lawsuit</title>
      <link>/post/monmouth-opra-case/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/monmouth-opra-case/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-recently-spoke-with-jersey-shore-online-https-www-jerseyshoreonline-com-ocean-county-lawsuit-questions-when-county-can-share-public-records-about-my-participation-in-a-multi-plaintiff-open-public-records-act-lawsuit-against-the-monmouth-county-nj-government-over-their-refusal-to-answer-requests-through-my-site-opramachine-https-opramachine-com&#34;&gt;I recently spoke with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jerseyshoreonline.com/ocean-county/lawsuit-questions-when-county-can-share-public-records/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jersey Shore Online&lt;/a&gt; about my participation in a multi-plaintiff Open Public Records Act lawsuit against the Monmouth County, NJ government over their refusal to answer requests through my site &lt;a href=&#34;https://opramachine.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;OPRAmachine&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lawsuit stems from the county&amp;rsquo;s refusal to answer legally valid public records requests submitted through the site, which automatically publishes public records requests &amp;amp; responses in all 21 counties of New Jersey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In its first year of existence, the civic technology and open government website - the first of its kind targeting New Jersey state &amp;amp; local government - has streamlined and modernized the public records request process in a paperless and easy to use process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monmouth County answered requests through the site without issue throughout 2017 and most of 2018 &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.opramachine.com/monmouth-opra-lawsuit/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;until one of their employees failed to redact confidential information.&lt;/a&gt;. When the county employees made a mistake, I took swift corrective action to remove the confidential material within 1 day of being contacted about the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the county chose to punish users of my site and refuse to answer any requests through the site after the incident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is unaccaptable and an obstruction of the county&amp;rsquo;s transparency obligations under OPRA, the state&amp;rsquo;s freedom of information law. I joined in the case to stand up for our users, who have faced stalls and delays on their records requests. OPRAmachine users includ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the portion of the story where I was quoted:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since announcing the lawsuit at the end of September, Rozzi has been working on changes to OPRAmachine. In an Oct. 9 email to Jersey Shore Online, he explained he’s been working to address privacy concerns raised by Monmouth County.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“By the end of the month, we anticipate that our changes will allow OPRAmachine to detect and automatically redact social security numbers to protect privacy interests, something that no other proprietary public records solution (that we are aware of in NJ) does,” Rozzi wrote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a separate email the same day, Rozzi explained exactly why he filed suit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We want the court to order Monmouth County to do as they have previously done and honor the legally valid public records requests submitted to them by our users. We hope that the lawsuit will stop the county from treating public records requests differently because they originate from the OPRAmachine service. To remedy the county’s obstruction of the public records request process, we are urging the court to strike down the county’s unprecedented and overreaching policy that limits access to public information and find them in violation of the law.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;read-the-full-story-at-jersey-shore-online-https-www-jerseyshoreonline-com-ocean-county-lawsuit-questions-when-county-can-share-public-records&#34;&gt;Read the full story at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jerseyshoreonline.com/ocean-county/lawsuit-questions-when-county-can-share-public-records/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jersey Shore Online&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rozzi v. Office of the Attorney General</title>
      <link>/legal/rozzivoag/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/legal/rozzivoag/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;attorney-general-s-office-violated-public-records-law-by-witholding-email-logs&#34;&gt;Attorney General&amp;rsquo;s Office violated public records law by witholding email logs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Legal Counsel: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pashmanstein.com/attorney/cj-griffin&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CJ Griffin, Esq.&lt;/a&gt; - Pashman Stein Walder Hayden&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The New Jersey Attorney General&amp;rsquo;s Office was found to have violated the Open Public Records Act by denying my request for copies of email logs for the OAG&amp;rsquo;s custodian of records. I requested the email logs as a part of my advocacy on behalf of my statewide freedom of information website, &lt;a href=&#34;/project/opramachine/&#34;&gt;OPRAmachine&lt;/a&gt;. The email logs provided insight into the practices of OAG when it comes to handling OPRA requests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;question-presented&#34;&gt;Question Presented&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Was the New Jersey Attorney General&amp;rsquo;s Office&amp;rsquo;s denial of a request for copies for email logs - on the basis that all of the logs should be withheld because a portion contained confidential information - a violation of the Open Public Records Act, N.J.S.A. 47:1A-1 et seq.?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;holding&#34;&gt;Holding&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Judge Mary Jacobson, A.J.S.C. held that the Attorney General&amp;rsquo;s refusal to produce the logs as originally requested constituted a violation of OPRA and ordered the OAG to disclose the requested email logs that were responsive to the initial public records request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;outcome&#34;&gt;Outcome&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Attorney General&amp;rsquo;s office eventually complied with the court order and &lt;a href=&#34;/post/rozzi-oag/&#34;&gt;turned over the responsive email logs.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the interest of saving resources, I voluntarily waived the portions of the email logs that did not pertain to the deputy attorney general&amp;rsquo;s other roles outside of complying with the state&amp;rsquo;s Open Public Records Act in order to prevent any further delays to accessing the requested public records.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;case-documents&#34;&gt;Case documents&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/files/Rozzi-AG Verified Complaint.pdf&#34;&gt;Read my verified complaint&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/post/rozzi-oag/&#34;&gt;Read my blog post about the documents they released&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Document Production in Rozzi v. OAG</title>
      <link>/post/rozzi-oag/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/rozzi-oag/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently obtained &lt;a href=&#34;/files/OAGemaillogs.pdf&#34;&gt;the following documents&lt;/a&gt; from the New Jersey Attorney General&amp;rsquo;s Office (OAG) which were produced in response to a court order isued in my lawsuit against the OAG. The documents were copies of email logs that show messages sent and received by the OAG&amp;rsquo;s custodian of records, who is responsible for complying with the provision of the New Jersey Open Public Records Act (OPRA) by way of responding to requests made under the state freedom of information law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/files/Rozzi-AG Verified Complaint.pdf&#34;&gt;My lawsuit&lt;/a&gt;, which was filed in Mercer County Superior Court, resulted in an an order for the Attorney General&amp;rsquo;s office to produce the (redacted) copies of the documents that I originally requested back in November, 2017. Additional delays were added by the fact that the documents required a significant number of redactions due to the OPRA custodian&amp;rsquo;s additional responsibilities in the OAG, such as those related to homeland security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My attorney, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pashmanstein.com/attorney/cj-griffin&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CJ Griffin, Esq.&lt;/a&gt; ultimately prevailed over the creative legal argument advanced by the AG&amp;rsquo;s Office. The AG&amp;rsquo;s legal position was particularly novel because the legal briefings cited OPRA cases as old as 2004 while essentially attempting to pretend the New Jersey Supreme Court&amp;rsquo;s ruling in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nj.com/politics/index.ssf/2017/03/nj_supreme_court_ruling_could_reshape_what_governm.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Paff v. Galloway Township&lt;/a&gt; (2017) never happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;I have an &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/OPRA?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#OPRA&lt;/a&gt; hearing tomorrow. Last year our Supreme Court ruled in Paff v Galloway that a request for a log of emails is a valid OPRA request. The State refuses to follow it and is asking the court to apply case law from 2004, as if Paff never happened. Updates to come&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; CJ Griffin, Esq. (@CJGriffinEsq) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/CJGriffinEsq/status/983515006556934144?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;April 10, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both the documents that were recently produced by the OAG in response to Judge Mary Jacobson, A.J.S.C.&amp;rsquo;s ruling in this case are available on the original &lt;a href=&#34;https://opramachine.com/request/email_logs_for_bruce_solomon_oag#incoming-3248&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;request thread on OPRAmachine.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Libertarians for Transparent Government v. New Jersey State Police</title>
      <link>/legal/njsplawsuit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/legal/njsplawsuit/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;new-jersey-state-police-held-accountable-in-court-for-stalling-on-public-records-requests&#34;&gt;New Jersey State Police held accountable in court for stalling on public records requests&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The case Libertarians for Transparent Government v. New Jersey State Police was an important case that revealed unacceptable practices by the New Jersey State Police.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The case revealed a pattern and practice of failure to comply with the requirements of the state&amp;rsquo;s Open Public Records Act (OPRA) after a judge in the case issued a ruling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I participated in the case by way of filing a certification detailing my experience with attempting to obtain helicopter usage logs
for then-New Jersey Governor Chris Christie&amp;rsquo;s usage of State Police helicopters. My certification details my own experience with the State Police and how they took repeated extensions prior to providing me with heavily redacted helicopter usage records.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;case-documents&#34;&gt;Case documents&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/files/Cert of Gavin Rozzi for Libertarians-SP2.pdf&#34;&gt;Read my certification&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B66zM58TlOVKRTZERjNvNm1xM0U/view&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Read the full complaint&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rozzi v. Lacey Township Board of Education</title>
      <link>/legal/rozzivlaceyboe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/legal/rozzivlaceyboe/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fee-demand-for-public-records-declared-unreasonable-and-unwarranted&#34;&gt;Fee demand for public records declared &amp;ldquo;unreasonable and unwarranted&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Legal Counsel: Pro Se&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GRC Complaint 2015-224&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Statutory provision at issue: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nj.gov/grc/pdf/OPRASpecialServiceCharge.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;N.J.S.A. 47:1A-5(c.)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After being on their docket for close to two years, the New Jersey Government Records Council (GRC) ruled in my favor after I filed a complaint captioned Gavin C. Rozzi v. Lacey Township Board of Education, GRC complaint 2015-224. The GRC ordered the Lacey Township Board of Education to refund an $85 &amp;ldquo;special service fee&amp;rdquo; the board&amp;rsquo;s business administrator imposed for copies of checks that showed the board&amp;rsquo;s contracted attorney received health benefits through a school district plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;question-presented&#34;&gt;Question Presented&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did the Lacey Township Board of Education&amp;rsquo;s imposition of an $85 &amp;ldquo;special service fee&amp;rdquo; for copies of checks that showed the school board attorney - a contracted professional - was receiving health benefits through a district plan violate the Open Public Records Act, N.J.S.A. 47:1A-1 et seq.?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;holding&#34;&gt;Holding&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The GRC held that the special service fee was &amp;ldquo;unreasonable and unwarranted&amp;rdquo; and issued an interim order compelling the district to refund the $85 &amp;ldquo;special service fee&amp;rdquo; that was charged to me before I could receive the requested records.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I filed the complaint because it was my belief that the true purpose of the fee was the chill public records requests rather than legitimately recover expenses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;case-documents&#34;&gt;Case documents&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/files/2015-224.pdf&#34;&gt;Final Decision - Rozzi v. Lacey Township Board of Education&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rozzi v. Ocean County Prosecutor&#39;s Office</title>
      <link>/legal/rozzivocp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/legal/rozzivocp/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Legal Counsel: Pro Se&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GRC Complaint 2015-250&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Statutory provision at issue: &lt;a href=&#34;https://law.justia.com/codes/new-jersey/2017/title-47/section-47-1a-5/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;N.J.S.A. 47:1A-5(g.) &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Question Presented&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did the Ocean County Prosecutor&amp;rsquo;s Office violate OPRA by failing to provide a response&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Holding&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;New Jersey Government Records Council (GRC)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;response provided to an Open Public Records Act (OPRA) request was legally insufficient under the OPRA law&amp;rsquo;s requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This case was filed at the same time a lawsuit that was filed against the OCPO by open government activist Harry Scheeler. Scheeler&amp;rsquo;s lawsuit sought similar documents as those that were issue in this case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;outcome&#34;&gt;Outcome&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the GRC did indeed find a violation of OPRA on the part of the county prosecutor&amp;rsquo;s office, they did not order the prosecutor&amp;rsquo;s office to produce any documents or find a &amp;ldquo;knowing and willful&amp;rdquo; violation of OPRA. It should note that the records custodian who was at the center of this case would would later be removed from his position, with his social media posts even going so far as to call for&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;case-documents&#34;&gt;Case documents&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/files/2015-250.pdf&#34;&gt;Final decision - Rozzi v. Ocean County Prosecutor&amp;rsquo;s Office&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
