<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OPRAmachine on Gavin Rozzi</title>
    <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/tags/opramachine/</link>
    <description>Recent content in OPRAmachine on Gavin Rozzi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2013-2018 Gavin Rozzi</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.gavinrozzi.com/tags/opramachine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview with AEA-NJ Newsletter</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/aea-nj-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/aea-nj-interview/</guid>
      <description>My work with OPRAmachine recently saw me interviewed by the newsletter of an organization that represents the interests of local and county utilities authorities around the state.
Eric San Juan, a writer for the Association of Environmental Authorities of New Jersey&amp;rsquo;s newsletter, interviewed me earlier in the summer about the impact of my statewide freedom of information platform, OPRAmachine.
The AEA-NJ was interested in OPRAmachine because their member authorities are subject to the state&amp;rsquo;s freedom of information law, the New Jersey Open Public Records Act.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OPRAmachine update: The $1000 email metadata &amp; other pushback from government agencies</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/621-om-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/621-om-update/</guid>
      <description>I was once again interviewed by Citizens&amp;rsquo; Media TV&amp;rsquo;s Jeff Epstein about my work with public records &amp;amp; transparency via the OPRAmachine statwewide freedom of information portal that I run.
Epstein serves as one of the site&amp;rsquo;s volunteer administrators and in this podcast recorded on June 21st, 2018 we discuss some of the challenges that we have encountered running the site, including pushback from government agencies, fee demands for public records &amp;amp; more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Document Production in Rozzi v. OAG</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/rozzi-oag/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/rozzi-oag/</guid>
      <description>I recently obtained the following documents from the New Jersey Attorney General&amp;rsquo;s Office (OAG) which were produced in response to a court order isued in my lawsuit against the OAG. The documents were copies of email logs that show messages sent and received by the OAG&amp;rsquo;s custodian of records, who is responsible for complying with the provision of the New Jersey Open Public Records Act (OPRA) by way of responding to requests made under the state freedom of information law.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Conversation With Jeff Epstein and Patrick Duff Re: OPRA &amp; Open Government</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/jeffpatrickopra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/jeffpatrickopra/</guid>
      <description>I recently spoke with Citizens&amp;rsquo; Media TV&amp;rsquo;s Jeff Epstein and Patrick Duff for an audio interview.
Our conversation centered on the Open Public Records Act (OPRA), transparency &amp;amp; open government issues centered on my work with public records and how the three of us have made use of my OPRAmachine platform.
Epstein is an independent journalist who I&amp;rsquo;ve previously collaborated with on various projects, and he also has a role with OPRAmachine where has serves as one of the site&amp;rsquo;s administrators since its inception in 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discussing OPRAmachine&#39;s Impact With WLFR Radio&#39;s Bill Watt</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/watt-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/watt-interview/</guid>
      <description>On on April 5th, 2018 I joined WLFR Radio&amp;rsquo;s Watt&amp;rsquo;s The Move, Stocton University&amp;rsquo;show own radio show that focuses on poliitics and public affairs.
During my one hour segment I discussed my work on several fronts. Our interview began with talk of my work with my first and most successful project, Ocean County Politics and later pivoted to my work with the OPRAmachine freedom of information portal and how it is making New Jersey government more transparent as a result of its impact.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>