<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>opra | Gavin Rozzi</title>
    <link>/tags/opra/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tags/opra/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>opra</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/thumbnail.jpg</url>
      <title>opra</title>
      <link>/tags/opra/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest Speaker: Democratic Club of Waretown</title>
      <link>/talk/waretown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/waretown/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/u4QCiMxFHyw&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coombs et al. v. County of Monmouth</title>
      <link>/legal/coombsmonmouth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/legal/coombsmonmouth/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Legal Counsel: Walter Luers, Esq.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Docket No.: MON-L-003195-18&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Statutory provision at issue: &lt;a href=&#34;https://law.justia.com/codes/new-jersey/2017/title-47/section-47-1a-6/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;N.J.S.A. 47:1A-6(g.) &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Question Presented&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can the Monmouth County, NJ government deny OPRA requests solely on the basis that they will be automatically published online?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Holding&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Monmouth County Superior Court&lt;/strong&gt;, Assignment Judge Lisa P. Thornton ruled that the county violated the Open Public Records Act by denying requests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Outcome&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monmouth County was ordered to respond to records requests via OPRAmachine, ending the denials that took place from 2018-19 under the new policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;case-documents&#34;&gt;Case documents&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/files/Coombsruling.pdf&#34;&gt;Final decision - Coombs et al. v. County of Monmouth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A data-driven approach to combatting addiction</title>
      <link>/talk/occopiatecrisis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/occopiatecrisis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After the presentation, Ocean County College addiction studies students are going to implement the concepts discussed in the talk &lt;a href=&#34;/files/ALDC 101 Term Project Assignment.pdf&#34;&gt;in order to complete their term project.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project is going to see students use public records to identify trends in overdose incidents and drug activity in their communities. The students will use the data to write a memo to their local decisionmakers and make three recommendations about how to combat addiction, making citations to the data they obtain.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video: Defeating redactions on poorly redacted documents</title>
      <link>/post/redactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/redactions/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0NnuA8RMyiY&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re like me and frequently deal with requesting public records, then you&amp;rsquo;ll be accustomed to receiving documents that have blocks of text redacted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Redactions are most often used by government officials to apply exemptions to the various federal and state public records law. Often, they&amp;rsquo;ll be used to obscure information that may breach confidentiality protections or needlessly harm the personal privacy of individuals. In other instances, redactions are somtimes abused to keep the lid on politically damaging revelations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not all redactions are created equal. In most cases, public entities are able to suitably redact documents either using computer-based solutions or with a good old fashioned black marker and copy machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes public entities get it wrong and end up using programs such as Microsoft Office or other basic editors that weren&amp;rsquo;t designed with permanently removing redacted information in mind, which allows the digitial files to be edited to reveal the information that was intended to be kept hidden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Flordia, a newspaper recently took a document that was publicly posted on an official websited and used computer software to remove the redactions and report on the confidential information contained in the publicly available report regarding Parkland school shooter Nikolas Cruz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Florida judge who presided over public records litigation concerning the original release of the report quickly blasted the newspaper, and demonstrated technical ignorance with regard to how the details were obtained by the newspaper&amp;rsquo;s reporters. School board lawyers attempted to frame the publication of the information as a violation of a previous court order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Video of the judge&amp;rsquo;s remarks was quickly posted to social media, where it circulated:
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Tough to watch. &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/7sSD40Wa5o&#34;&gt;https://t.co/7sSD40Wa5o&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Gavin Rozzi (@gavroz) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/gavroz/status/1030224010532057089?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;August 16, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my own video embedded above in this blog post, I use one of my own past public records requests to demonstrate how removing redactions and accessing hidden material is possible when public officials improperly attempt to redact information. The video shows the end result of me using Adobe Acrobat to delete the black boxes of text used to &amp;ldquo;redact&amp;rdquo; information from email logs provided in response to a 2017 public records request from a New Jersey school district.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While these instances are not common, journalists owe it to themselves to double check the documents that they receive in response to their public records requests, as sometimes the mistakes of government agencies may work to the benefit of your story.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using OPRAmachine to file public records requests without the hassle</title>
      <link>/talk/montclair/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/montclair/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recorded video of webinar:

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_1E2tWOOWzU&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join me in late August at the Montclair University &lt;a href=&#34;https://centerforcooperativemedia.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Center for Cooperative Media&lt;/a&gt; to talk about my recent work with &lt;a href=&#34;/project/opramachine&#34;&gt;OPRAmachine&lt;/a&gt; and give a step-by-step demonstration along with taking audience questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here is their official announcement of the event, copied below:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Opening up New Jersey government, one request at a time.&amp;rdquo; That&amp;rsquo;s the tagline of OPRAmachine.com, a free tool created by New Jersey&amp;rsquo;s own Gavin Rozzi and available for all to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every citizen has the right to access public records held by state &amp;amp; local government agencies under the New Jersey Open Public Records Act (OPRA). By law, they have to respond. The problem is, the process for requesting those documents isn&amp;rsquo;t always as easy and straightforward as it should be – until now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join this webinar and Rozzi will show you the simple, step-by-step process for filing OPRA requests and browsing OPRAmachine to see what public records and information others have requested&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Register for the event at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/using-opramachine-to-file-public-records-requests-without-the-hassle-tickets-48653465826?aff=efbeventtix&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Eventbrite&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rozzi v. Office of the Attorney General</title>
      <link>/legal/rozzivoag/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/legal/rozzivoag/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;attorney-general-s-office-violated-public-records-law-by-witholding-email-logs&#34;&gt;Attorney General&amp;rsquo;s Office violated public records law by witholding email logs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Legal Counsel: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pashmanstein.com/attorney/cj-griffin&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CJ Griffin, Esq.&lt;/a&gt; - Pashman Stein Walder Hayden&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The New Jersey Attorney General&amp;rsquo;s Office was found to have violated the Open Public Records Act by denying my request for copies of email logs for the OAG&amp;rsquo;s custodian of records. I requested the email logs as a part of my advocacy on behalf of my statewide freedom of information website, &lt;a href=&#34;/project/opramachine/&#34;&gt;OPRAmachine&lt;/a&gt;. The email logs provided insight into the practices of OAG when it comes to handling OPRA requests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;question-presented&#34;&gt;Question Presented&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Was the New Jersey Attorney General&amp;rsquo;s Office&amp;rsquo;s denial of a request for copies for email logs - on the basis that all of the logs should be withheld because a portion contained confidential information - a violation of the Open Public Records Act, N.J.S.A. 47:1A-1 et seq.?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;holding&#34;&gt;Holding&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Judge Mary Jacobson, A.J.S.C. held that the Attorney General&amp;rsquo;s refusal to produce the logs as originally requested constituted a violation of OPRA and ordered the OAG to disclose the requested email logs that were responsive to the initial public records request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;outcome&#34;&gt;Outcome&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Attorney General&amp;rsquo;s office eventually complied with the court order and &lt;a href=&#34;/post/rozzi-oag/&#34;&gt;turned over the responsive email logs.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the interest of saving resources, I voluntarily waived the portions of the email logs that did not pertain to the deputy attorney general&amp;rsquo;s other roles outside of complying with the state&amp;rsquo;s Open Public Records Act in order to prevent any further delays to accessing the requested public records.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;case-documents&#34;&gt;Case documents&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/files/Rozzi-AG Verified Complaint.pdf&#34;&gt;Read my verified complaint&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/post/rozzi-oag/&#34;&gt;Read my blog post about the documents they released&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Libertarians for Transparent Government v. New Jersey State Police</title>
      <link>/legal/njsplawsuit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/legal/njsplawsuit/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;new-jersey-state-police-held-accountable-in-court-for-stalling-on-public-records-requests&#34;&gt;New Jersey State Police held accountable in court for stalling on public records requests&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The case Libertarians for Transparent Government v. New Jersey State Police was an important case that revealed unacceptable practices by the New Jersey State Police.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The case revealed a pattern and practice of failure to comply with the requirements of the state&amp;rsquo;s Open Public Records Act (OPRA) after a judge in the case issued a ruling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I participated in the case by way of filing a certification detailing my experience with attempting to obtain helicopter usage logs
for then-New Jersey Governor Chris Christie&amp;rsquo;s usage of State Police helicopters. My certification details my own experience with the State Police and how they took repeated extensions prior to providing me with heavily redacted helicopter usage records.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;case-documents&#34;&gt;Case documents&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/files/Cert of Gavin Rozzi for Libertarians-SP2.pdf&#34;&gt;Read my certification&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B66zM58TlOVKRTZERjNvNm1xM0U/view&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Read the full complaint&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rozzi v. Lacey Township Board of Education</title>
      <link>/legal/rozzivlaceyboe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/legal/rozzivlaceyboe/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fee-demand-for-public-records-declared-unreasonable-and-unwarranted&#34;&gt;Fee demand for public records declared &amp;ldquo;unreasonable and unwarranted&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Legal Counsel: Pro Se&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GRC Complaint 2015-224&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Statutory provision at issue: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nj.gov/grc/pdf/OPRASpecialServiceCharge.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;N.J.S.A. 47:1A-5(c.)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After being on their docket for close to two years, the New Jersey Government Records Council (GRC) ruled in my favor after I filed a complaint captioned Gavin C. Rozzi v. Lacey Township Board of Education, GRC complaint 2015-224. The GRC ordered the Lacey Township Board of Education to refund an $85 &amp;ldquo;special service fee&amp;rdquo; the board&amp;rsquo;s business administrator imposed for copies of checks that showed the board&amp;rsquo;s contracted attorney received health benefits through a school district plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;question-presented&#34;&gt;Question Presented&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did the Lacey Township Board of Education&amp;rsquo;s imposition of an $85 &amp;ldquo;special service fee&amp;rdquo; for copies of checks that showed the school board attorney - a contracted professional - was receiving health benefits through a district plan violate the Open Public Records Act, N.J.S.A. 47:1A-1 et seq.?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;holding&#34;&gt;Holding&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The GRC held that the special service fee was &amp;ldquo;unreasonable and unwarranted&amp;rdquo; and issued an interim order compelling the district to refund the $85 &amp;ldquo;special service fee&amp;rdquo; that was charged to me before I could receive the requested records.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I filed the complaint because it was my belief that the true purpose of the fee was the chill public records requests rather than legitimately recover expenses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;case-documents&#34;&gt;Case documents&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/files/2015-224.pdf&#34;&gt;Final Decision - Rozzi v. Lacey Township Board of Education&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rozzi v. Ocean County Prosecutor&#39;s Office</title>
      <link>/legal/rozzivocp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/legal/rozzivocp/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Legal Counsel: Pro Se&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GRC Complaint 2015-250&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Statutory provision at issue: &lt;a href=&#34;https://law.justia.com/codes/new-jersey/2017/title-47/section-47-1a-5/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;N.J.S.A. 47:1A-5(g.) &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Question Presented&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did the Ocean County Prosecutor&amp;rsquo;s Office violate OPRA by failing to provide a response&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Holding&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;New Jersey Government Records Council (GRC)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;response provided to an Open Public Records Act (OPRA) request was legally insufficient under the OPRA law&amp;rsquo;s requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This case was filed at the same time a lawsuit that was filed against the OCPO by open government activist Harry Scheeler. Scheeler&amp;rsquo;s lawsuit sought similar documents as those that were issue in this case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;outcome&#34;&gt;Outcome&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the GRC did indeed find a violation of OPRA on the part of the county prosecutor&amp;rsquo;s office, they did not order the prosecutor&amp;rsquo;s office to produce any documents or find a &amp;ldquo;knowing and willful&amp;rdquo; violation of OPRA. It should note that the records custodian who was at the center of this case would would later be removed from his position, with his social media posts even going so far as to call for&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;case-documents&#34;&gt;Case documents&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/files/2015-250.pdf&#34;&gt;Final decision - Rozzi v. Ocean County Prosecutor&amp;rsquo;s Office&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
