<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Radio on Gavin Rozzi</title>
    <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/tags/radio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Radio on Gavin Rozzi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2013-2018 Gavin Rozzi</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.gavinrozzi.com/tags/radio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Reimagining the police scanner in the era of the software defined radio</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/talk/ocradiodefcon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/talk/ocradiodefcon/</guid>
      <description>Recorded video of talk:   &amp;nbsp;
I will be speaking about my experience implementing open source software and working the RTLSDR platform to create an online timeshifting police, fire &amp;amp; EMS scanner that outperforms commercially availalble hardware scanners in many respects.
Use the video link above to watch this talk live on the date of the event. The time of this event has been changed to Eastern Standard Time for its posting on this website due to the difference in timezones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big upgrades to OC Radio Live</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/ocrl-update-72918/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/post/ocrl-update-72918/</guid>
      <description>Today I am proud to announce that we have added a significant number of new channels to Ocean County Radio Live, my online police fire &amp;amp; EMS scanner and archive service. The service now supports listening to two 700 MHz digital trunked radio systems, Ocean County&amp;rsquo;s and the New Jersey Interoperability Communications System, which hosts channels for the State Police, Fish &amp;amp; Wildlife and numerous other state and local agencies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ocean County Radio Live</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/ocradiolive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/ocradiolive/</guid>
      <description>The new way to scan Ocean County Ocean County Radio Live is taking the technical complexity and hassle out of radio scanning in Ocean County, New Jersey. This website was launched in late January, 2018 and since that date has continued to stream &amp;amp; archive multiple police, fire &amp;amp; EMS radio channels.
This website is powered by the latest software defined radio (SDR) technology to process the streams of digital data produced by the Ocean County trunked radio system and also record analog conventional systems used by some departments &amp;amp; squads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forked River Amateur Radio Club</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/frnjarc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/frnjarc/</guid>
      <description>Serving the Forked River, NJ amateur radio community The Forked River Amateur Radio Club is a new amateur radio club formed to serve amateur radio community of Forked River, NJ and surrounding areas. I currently serve as both the vice president and webmaster of the club. We anticipate on pursuing several projects through this club, such as 2 meter FM repeater and 70 cm band DMR system to cover the Lacey area.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>