<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Gavin Rozzi</title>
    <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Gavin Rozzi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2013-2018 Gavin Rozzi</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Rozzi v. Office of the Attorney General</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/rozzivoag/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/rozzivoag/</guid>
      <description>Attorney General&amp;rsquo;s Office violated public records law by witholding email logs Legal Counsel: CJ Griffin, Esq. - Pashman Stein Walder Hayden
The New Jersey Attorney General&amp;rsquo;s Office was found to have violated the Open Public Records Act by denying my request for copies of email logs for the OAG&amp;rsquo;s custodian of records. I requested the email logs as a part of my advocacy on behalf of my statewide freedom of information website, OPRAmachine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Libertarians for Transparent Government v. New Jersey State Police</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/njsplawsuit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/njsplawsuit/</guid>
      <description>New Jersey State Police held accountable in court for stalling on public records requests The case Libertarians for Transparent Government v. New Jersey State Police was an important case that revealed unacceptable practices by the New Jersey State Police.
The case revealed a pattern and practice of failure to comply with the requirements of the state&amp;rsquo;s Open Public Records Act (OPRA) after a judge in the case issued a ruling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OPRAmachine</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/opramachine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/opramachine/</guid>
      <description>Opening up New Jersey government OPRAmachine.com is a first of its kind government transparency project that I recently launched to serve the citizens of the state of New Jersey. The site is powered by the New Jersey Open Public Records Act (OPRA), a freedom of information law that allows any citizen of the state to request public records from state and local government agencies.
How it works OPRAmachine is breaking down barriers by explaining aspects of the OPRA request process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ocean County Radio Live</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/ocradiolive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/ocradiolive/</guid>
      <description>The new way to scan Ocean County Ocean County Radio Live is taking the technical complexity and hassle out of radio scanning in Ocean County, New Jersey. This website was launched in late January, 2018 and since that date has continued to stream &amp;amp; archive multiple police, fire &amp;amp; EMS radio channels.
This website is powered by the latest software defined radio (SDR) technology to process the streams of digital data produced by the Ocean County trunked radio system and also record analog conventional systems used by some departments &amp;amp; squads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forked River Amateur Radio Club</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/frnjarc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/frnjarc/</guid>
      <description>Serving the Forked River, NJ amateur radio community The Forked River Amateur Radio Club is a new amateur radio club formed to serve amateur radio community of Forked River, NJ and surrounding areas. I currently serve as both the vice president and webmaster of the club. We anticipate on pursuing several projects through this club, such as 2 meter FM repeater and 70 cm band DMR system to cover the Lacey area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JerseyLeaks</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/jerseyleaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/jerseyleaks/</guid>
      <description>Enabling whistleblowers to report public corruption JerseyLeaks is a public corruption whistleblowing &amp;amp; transparaency initiative. The site serves as a collaborative journalism tool that allows sources to confidentially leak documents to reporters using an encrypted online system. The documents are encrypted at rest and in transit using the OpenPGP public keys of journalists using the open-source Globaleaks software, ensuring the privacy of sources. The system allows whistleblowers with knowledge of public corruption to submit documents to journalists who may publish them as a part of an investigative story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ocean County Politics</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/politicsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/politicsoc/</guid>
      <description>Ocean County&amp;rsquo;s source political news &amp;amp; commentary Ocean County Politics is an independent news website that covers politics and public affairs in the greater Ocean County, NJ region. Ocean County Politics has become known for publishing in-depth accounts of county and municipal governmental activities and behind-the-scenes activities that influence the county&amp;rsquo;s political climate.
In addition to providing insightful commentary and news, the site also features reader contributed op-eds and letters to the editor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rozzi v. Lacey Township Board of Education</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/rozzivlaceyboe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/rozzivlaceyboe/</guid>
      <description>Fee demand for public records declared &amp;ldquo;unreasonable and unwarranted&amp;rdquo; Legal Counsel: Pro Se
GRC Complaint 2015-224
Statutory provision at issue: N.J.S.A. 47:1A-5(c.)
After being on their docket for close to two years, the New Jersey Government Records Council (GRC) ruled in my favor after I filed a complaint captioned Gavin C. Rozzi v. Lacey Township Board of Education, GRC complaint 2015-224. The GRC ordered the Lacey Township Board of Education to refund an $85 &amp;ldquo;special service fee&amp;rdquo; the board&amp;rsquo;s business administrator imposed for copies of checks that showed the board&amp;rsquo;s contracted attorney received health benefits through a school district plan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rozzi v. Ocean County Prosecutor&#39;s Office</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/rozzivocp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/rozzivocp/</guid>
      <description>Legal Counsel: Pro Se
GRC Complaint 2015-250
Statutory provision at issue: N.J.S.A. 47:1A-5(g.) 
Question Presented
Did the Ocean County Prosecutor&amp;rsquo;s Office violate OPRA by failing to provide a response
Holding
The New Jersey Government Records Council (GRC)
response provided to an Open Public Records Act (OPRA) request was legally insufficient under the OPRA law&amp;rsquo;s requirements.
This case was filed at the same time a lawsuit that was filed against the OCPO by open government activist Harry Scheeler.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toms River 911 Call Explorer</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/tomsriver-911/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/project/tomsriver-911/</guid>
      <description>The Toms River 911 Call Explorer is a small web development project that I created in the summer of 2018 order to make visualzing data that I obtained using an OPRA request.
Content on the website is rendered using the Hugo static site generator, with the request thread on OPRAmachine hosting the actual CSV file with 911 call data.
Columns from the CSV file are rendered on the homepage of the site after being pulled from OPRAmachine.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>