<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Gavin Rozzi</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Gavin Rozzi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017-18 Gavin C. Rozzi.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/project/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Forked River Amateur Radio Club</title>
      <link>/project/frnjarc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/frnjarc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Forked River Amateur Radio Club is a new club recently formed to serve amateur radio community of Forked River, NJ and surrounding areas. I currently serve as both the vice president and webmaster of the club. We anticipate on pursuing several projects through this club, such as 2 meter FM repeater and 70 cm band DMR system to cover the Lacey area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://frnjarc.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;View the club&amp;rsquo;s website here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JerseyLeaks</title>
      <link>/project/jerseyleaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/jerseyleaks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JerseyLeaks is a whistleblowing and collaborative journalism tool that allows
sources to confidentially leak documents to reporters using an encrypted online system.
The system allows whistleblowers with knowledge of public corruption to submit documents to journalists who may publish them as a part of an investigative story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project has been a collaborative effort and other journalists are invited to join the platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jerseyleaks.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;View JerseyLeaks at this link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://submit.jerseyleaks.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Submit documents here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ocean County Politics</title>
      <link>/project/politicsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/politicsoc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I use this blog to cover politics and public affairs in the greater Ocean County, NJ region. Ocean County Politics has become known for publishing in-depth accounts of county and municipal governmental activities and behind-the-scenes activities that influence the county&amp;rsquo;s political climate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://politicsoc.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Read Ocean County Politics here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rozzi v. Lacey Township Board of Education</title>
      <link>/project/rozzivlaceyboe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/rozzivlaceyboe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The New Jersey Government Records Council (GRC) ruled in my favor and ordered the
Lacey Township Board of Education to refund an $85 &amp;ldquo;special service fee&amp;rdquo; they attempted
to charge me for copies of checks that showed the board&amp;rsquo;s contracted attorney was receiving health benefits through a school plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/files/2015-224.pdf&#34;&gt;Read the full decision from the GRC here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rozzi v. Ocean County Prosecutor&#39;s Office</title>
      <link>/project/rozzivocp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/rozzivocp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The New Jersey Government Records Council (GRC) ruled in my favor and declared that the
response provided to an Open Public Records Act (OPRA) request was legally insufficient under the OPRA law&amp;rsquo;s requirements. The GRC complaint was filed in 2015 and was adjudicated by the GRC after a nearly two-year wait time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This case was filed at the same time a lawsuit that was filed against the OCPO by open government activist Harry Scheeler. Scheeler&amp;rsquo;s lawsuit sought similar documents as those that were issue in this case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/files/2015-250.pdf&#34;&gt;Read the full decision from the GRC here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OPRAmachine</title>
      <link>/project/opramachine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/opramachine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;OPRAmachine.com is a first of its kind government transparency project to launch in New Jersey. The site allows any citizen to easily file a legally valid public records request under New Jersey&amp;rsquo;s state freedom of information law, the Open Public Records Act (OPRA). The site has enabled requesters to obtain thousands of pages worth of public records, helping to shine a light on some of the more obscure elements of New Jersey state and local government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The site has been making an impact and has been used as a research tool by public officials, journalists and activists seeking to obtain authoritative information about public entities in the state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://opramachine.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Check out OPRAmachine here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ocean County Scanner News</title>
      <link>/project/ocscannernews/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/ocscannernews/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ocean County Scanner News is a network of radio and emergency services enthusiasts who listen to
police scanners and post live news updates via their Facebook page. I designed the groups&amp;rsquo;s website
in addition to setting up a livestream server running the Icecast software package. The live feed covers
the Ocean County Trunked Radio system and several other local conventional channels. We are planning more
additions to the live feed as time and resources allow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ocscanner.news/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;View Ocean County Scanner News here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ocscanner.news:8000/stream&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Listen to Ocean County Scanner News live audio feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
