<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks on Gavin Rozzi</title>
    <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/talk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks on Gavin Rozzi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2013-2019 Gavin Rozzi</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.gavinrozzi.com/talk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A data-driven approach to combatting addiction</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/talk/occopiatecrisis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/talk/occopiatecrisis/</guid>
      <description>After the presentation, Ocean County College addiction studies students are going to implement the concepts discussed in the talk in order to complete their term project.
The project is going to see students use public records to identify trends in overdose incidents and drug activity in their communities. The students will use the data to write a memo to their local decisionmakers and make three recommendations about how to combat addiction, making citations to the data they obtain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reimagining the police scanner in the era of the software defined radio</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/talk/ocradiodefcon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/talk/ocradiodefcon/</guid>
      <description>Recorded video of talk:   &amp;nbsp;
I will be speaking about my experience implementing open source software and working the RTLSDR platform to create an online timeshifting police, fire &amp;amp; EMS scanner that outperforms commercially availalble hardware scanners in many respects.
Use the video link above to watch this talk live on the date of the event. The time of this event has been changed to Eastern Standard Time for its posting on this website due to the difference in timezones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using OPRAmachine to file public records requests without the hassle</title>
      <link>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/talk/montclair/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.gavinrozzi.com/talk/montclair/</guid>
      <description>Recorded video of webinar:   &amp;nbsp;
Join me in late August at the Montclair University Center for Cooperative Media to talk about my recent work with OPRAmachine and give a step-by-step demonstration along with taking audience questions.
Here is their official announcement of the event, copied below:
&amp;ldquo;Opening up New Jersey government, one request at a time.&amp;rdquo; That&amp;rsquo;s the tagline of OPRAmachine.com, a free tool created by New Jersey&amp;rsquo;s own Gavin Rozzi and available for all to use.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>